We truly wish all of our cordial brothers and sisters
私たちの心からの兄弟姉妹の皆様のご冥福をお祈り申し上げます。
that fullyrs advocate for the restoration.
フラーたちは修復を主張しています。
Central Surgeon Center responds veryupply
中央外科医センターは非常に返答します
to the
に
Paul Davis's discourse.
ポール・デイヴィスの講演。
Pieters perhaps learn about
ピータースはおそらく次のことを学ぶでしょう
Welcome to the last feast of knowledge this year
今年最後の知識の饗宴へようこそ
So today's speaker, Dr. Lin Jiwen
それでは、今日の講演者、リン・ジウェン博士
Researcher and Director of the Institute of Political Science
研究者・政治学研究所所長
So he graduated from the Institute of Political Science, Department of Political Science, National Taiwan University?
ということは、彼は国立台湾大学政治学院政治学科を卒業したのですか？
also have
也有
Then, in 1996, UCLA awarded a Ph.D. degree in political science from this branch of the University of California
その後 1996 年に、UCLA はカリフォルニア大学のこの支部から政治学の博士号を授与しました。
then he is
それなら彼は
Taiwan's youth is the most famous political scientist I think
私が思うに台湾の若者で最も有名な政治学者は
Then it is the wild lily generation in the broad sense of this wild lily
では、このヤマユリの広義のヤマユリ世代です
Then his greatest interest is to understand why human beings establish norms to limit their freedom
彼の最大の関心は、なぜ人間が自由を制限する規範を設けるのかを理解することです
Why do humans establish norms to limit their freedom
なぜ人間は自由を制限する規範を設けるのか
Is it for greater freedom or for one group of people to dominate another
それはより大きな自由のためでしょうか、それともあるグループが別のグループを支配するためでしょうか
The answer to this question is of course very complex
もちろん、この質問に対する答えは非常に複雑です
to answer this question
この質問に答えるために
Dr Lin's Research Interests
リン博士の研究対象
Include the formal model
正式なモデルを含める
including comparative political systems
比較政治制度も含めて
and East Asian politics
そして東アジアの政治
and covers abstraction
抽象化をカバーします
Theoretical and local
理論的および局所的
Professor Lin's academic performance is very good
リン教授の学業成績は非常に良いです
He also passed the National Science Council
彼は国家科学会議にも合格した
Contact Home Now
今すぐホームに連絡する
Once a modeler of political science
かつては政治学のモデラーだった
he has two books
彼は本を2冊持っています
Papers are published in good Chinese and foreign journals
論文は中国および海外の優れた雑誌に掲載されています
Including Politics, Journal of Democracy
政治を含む、民主主義ジャーナル
China Quarterly
中国季報
Etc., etc
などなど
he was a very accomplished political scientist
彼は非常に優れた政治学者でした
At the same time, he also endows theoretical thinking
同時に、理論的思考も養います。
development of realpolitik
リアルポリティックの発展
also have very unique insights
非常にユニークな洞察力もあります
We have business talks with him every once in a while
私たちは彼と時々商談をします
Only then do I understand what Taiwan is now
そうして初めて台湾の今が分かる
what's going on in politics
政治で何が起こっているのか
including when we ate
食事をしたときも含めて
so that i can understand a little bit
少しでも理解できるように
understand a little bit
少しは理解できる
because i'm a historian
私は歴史家だから
history won't run away
歴史は逃げない
history is always there
歴史はいつもそこにある
so but politics is different
そうだけど政治は違う
different politics
異なる政治
politics it has been evolving
政治は進化し続けている
inattentive
不注意な
within a month
1ヶ月以内に
One thing can change Taiwan's political
一つのことが台湾の政治を変える可能性がある
Landscape changes it all
風景がすべてを変える
and it's changing very fast
そしてそれは非常に急速に変化しています
especially now social media
特に今はソーシャルメディア
Often a thing is not dealt with for a few days
物事が数日間処理されないことがよくあります
the whole situation changes
全体の状況が変わります
So this gets really fast
これは本当に速くなります
become very fast
とても速くなります
so every once in a while
だから時々
I'm going to get close
近づいてみます
I think the analysis is very accurate
分析は非常に正確だと思います
and theoretically valuable
そして理論的に価値がある
listen to what they have to say
彼らの言うことを聞いてください
Then take a look at the political situation in Taiwan
次に台湾の政治情勢を見てみます。
And your director is the most important one
そしてあなたのディレクターは最も重要な人物です
we applaud now
私たちは今拍手を送ります
come and welcome his speech today
今日の彼のスピーチを歓迎しに来てください
Thanks
ありがとう
i think i have to introduce myself first
まず自己紹介をしなければいけないと思います
This is so-called popular science
これはいわゆるポピュラーサイエンスです
Then you should know who I am
そうすれば、私が誰であるかわかるはずです
Then I want to introduce Wang Fu just now
それでは、王福を紹介したいと思います
Young Scholars
若い学者たち
It's actually very simple because there is no
実際には何もないので非常に簡単です
So I'm the first and the last
だから私は最初で最後です
because how to say
なぜなら、なんと言うか
when i got my doctorate
私が博士号を取得したとき
I was probably the first to run back to Taiwan
おそらく台湾に逃げ帰ったのは私が最初だったでしょう
so no one else so simple
だからこんなに単純な人は他にいない
ok
Ok
then i want to introduce myself first
それではまず自己紹介をしたいと思います
when i was in high school
私が高校にいたとき
In middle school and high school
中学や高校では
my favorite is english class
私のお気に入りは英語の授業です
my favorite is language
私のお気に入りは言語です
So I would choose the Department of Politics
だから私は政治学部を選びます
The international relations group is actually very simple
国際関係グループは実際には非常にシンプルです
I didn't even think about going into academia
大学に進学することも考えていなかった
then i want to be a diplomat
それから私は外交官になりたいです
it's easy
それは簡単です
High school students want to be diplomats
高校生は外交官になりたい
I think being a diplomat is so much fun.
外交官の仕事はとても楽しいと思います。
That was after I entered the political department
それは私が政治部に入ってからのことです
I regret the first study
最初の勉強を後悔している
why do you regret
なぜ後悔するのですか
I found Taiwan's diplomacy
台湾外交を見つけた
Countries with diplomatic relations are not there
国交のある国は存在しない
my seniors and sisters
私の先輩と妹たち
It's just that after entering the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, it's very hard.
ただ、外務省に入ってからは大変です。
I have a good senior
いい先輩がいるよ
He said you are now in the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
あなたは今外務省にいると彼は言いました
Mr. Li Bin, what are you doing?
李斌さん、何をしているのですか？
He said it was hard work
彼は大変な仕事だと言いました
say what are you doing
何をしているのか言ってください
He said I was opening the menu
彼は私がメニューを開いていると言いました
what menu
何のメニュー
He said because at that time
彼が言ったのは、その時だから
we still have a lot
私たちにはまだたくさんあります
that diplomatic relationship is in the middle east
その外交関係は中東にある
He said I'm going to notice
彼は私が気づくだろうと言いました
The first one is after I open the menu
1枚目はメニューを開いた後です
can't let them see me
彼らに私に会わせられない
because i'm female
私は女性なので
What about the second one? Those menus are horrible.
そして2番目はそれらのメニューはひどいです
Anyway, no need to describe
とにかく説明の必要はありません
You probably know what menu he serves
あなたはおそらく彼が提供するメニューを知っているでしょう
then he left
それから彼は去りました
So what I mean is
つまり、私が言いたいのは、
The so-called political science is actually quite complicated
いわゆる政治学は実際には非常に複雑です
But what we thought at the time
でも、その時私たちが思ったことは、
very simple
とてもシンプルな
I just think I'm going to study political science
政治学を勉強しようと思っているところです
I'm going to be a diplomat in the future
私は将来外交官になるつもりです
Later, I found out that this road can't go on.
後でわかったのですが、この道は進めません。
Then I passed by
それから私は通り過ぎました
Return to Academia Sinica after several years
数年後に中央研究院に復帰
I found that the average person's interest in political science
私は、平均的な人々の政治学への関心が高いことを発見しました。
Still have an interesting idea
まだ面白いアイデアがある
He said how could political science be called science?
彼は、どうして政治学を科学と呼べるだろうか、と言いました。
right
右
You should all still have this question now
皆さんも今でもこの疑問を抱いているはずです
How can political science be a science
政治学はどうして科学になり得るのか
We all know that in the humanities and social sciences
人文科学や社会科学では、私たちは皆それを知っています。
will put their own subjects
自分の主題を置くでしょう
Science is only political science
科学は政治学にすぎない
English called Political Science
政治学という英語
then nothing else
それなら他には何もない
What about others?
他の人はどうですか？
not so inferior
そんなに劣ってない
because we have to claim we're doing political science
なぜなら私たちは政治学をやっていると主張しなければならないからです
The second one is that many scholars
2つ目は、多くの学者がいることです。
When you think that political science is not a science
政治学は科学ではないと思うとき
So just talk about your theory
だからあなたの理論について話してください
ok
Ok
That is to say, if politics is not science
つまり、政治学が科学ではないとしたら、
So you're really like a humanities history?
ということは、本当に文系史っぽいんですか？
It seems not
そうではないようです
then we are in a very awkward position
その場合、私たちは非常に厄介な立場にいます
Then I think this impression is still quite deep.
そうすると、この印象は今でもかなり根深いのではないかと思います。
that's talking
それは話しています
Many people will say, why do you study political science?
多くの人は、なぜ政治学を学ぶのですかと言うでしょう。
ok
Ok
Like my mother asked me what are you studying in political science?
母が私に尋ねたように、政治学で何を勉強しているのですか？
If you don't run for president, what are you going to do?
大統領に立候補しないならどうするつもりですか？
ok
Ok
I said I was doing learning, how did he do good research
私は勉強をしていると言いましたが、彼はどうやって良い研究をしたのですか？
So now many people's impression of political science comes from Taiwan's education issues
現在、多くの人の政治学に対する印象は台湾の教育問題から来ている
Because we were divided into two groups in high school
高校の時に二つのグループに分かれていたから
Wen Group and Li Group
ウェングループとリーグループ
Well, we now have research that proves that
さて、私たちは今、それを証明する研究を行っています
He showed that in fact the group book of the high school
彼は実際に高校のグループブックにあることを示しました
is a bad thing
それは悪いことです
Why
なぜ
Because it will make the person in the selection team
選考チームに入る人になるから
I feel bad at math
数学が苦手な気がする
actually that's wrong
実際にはそれは間違っています
I remember being very impressed when I was a freshman
1年生の時にとても感動したのを覚えています
That is to say, among my classmates
つまりクラスメイトの中では
many people he said
多くの人が彼は言った
I finally don't have to study math anymore.
ついに数学を勉強する必要がなくなりました。
Many students in the literary group are like this, right?
文芸サークルの学生ってこういう人多いですよね？
I know many of you feel this way
多くの人がそう感じていることは知っています
Good thing I don't have to study math anymore
良かった、もう数学を勉強する必要がない
It gives me a headache to see that loss
あの損失を見ると頭が痛くなる
Many of my classmates are like this
私の同級生にはこういう人が多い
That's why you really want to study political science.
だからこそ、あなたは本当に政治学を学びたいのです。
you will find a very interesting thing
とても興味深いものを見つけるでしょう
That is to say
つまり
A topic I want to share with you today
今日皆さんと共有したいトピック
that is
あれは
How many look here
ここを見ている人は何人いますか
sorry
ごめん
Because I am used to writing in English
英語で書くことに慣れているので
I'll translate it
翻訳してみます
so-called political science
いわゆる政治学
with statistics and game theory
統計学とゲーム理論を使って
Wait a minute and I'll introduce what game theory is
ちょっと待ってください。ゲーム理論とは何かを紹介します
what does it matter
それは何ですか
OK
OK
so i put the question first
だから私は質問を最初に置きました
mean to say
言う意味
statistics
統計
Strategy
ストラテジー
The most important thing is that game theory is talking about Strategy
最も重要なことは、ゲーム理論は戦略について話しているということです
and political science
そして政治学
It's probably the core issue
おそらくそれが核心的な問題です
authority
権限
So what's the relationship between these three?
この3人の関係は何でしょうか？
Of course you'd think he had nothing to do with it.
もちろん、彼はそれとは何の関係もないと思うでしょう。
Actually he has nothing to do
実際のところ、彼には何もすることがない
But I think you look at it from a historical perspective
しかし、歴史的な観点から見ると思います
You'll find out that he's not only related
彼は血縁関係だけではないことがわかるだろう
and a very close relationship
そしてとても親密な関係
OK so today I am very
さて、今日はとても元気です
The purpose of the thousand generations is to let everyone know one thing
千代の目的は一つのことを皆に知らせることだ
That is to say, political science in the so-called social sciences
つまり、いわゆる社会科学の中の政治学です。
The statistics that everyone is talking about now
今みんなが話題にしている統計
game theory
ゲーム理論
His relationship is very close
彼の関係はとても親密です
even the closeness of his relationship
彼の関係の親密ささえも
more than other disciplines
他の分野よりも
ok then let's see
わかりました、それでは見てみましょう
Few people know who this man is
この男が誰であるかを知っている人はほとんどいません
I was chatting with Deputy Wang when we were eating
食事中に王副官とおしゃべりしていました
His name is Fal Noyman
彼の名前はファル・ノイマンです
John Fal Noyman
ジョン・ファル・ノイマン
So what do you think these three things are related to?
では、これら 3 つは何に関係していると思いますか?
one is to do
1つはやることです
One is to make yourself very powerful
1つは、自分自身を非常に強力にすることです
OK you have a lot to do
オーケー、やるべきことはたくさんある
Only then can I become a very powerful person
そうして初めて私はとても強い人間になれるのです
But you need to understand statistics
ただし統計を理解する必要がある
then you have to understand
それなら理解する必要があります
This Game Theory game theory
このゲーム理論 ゲーム理論
Maybe I'll think of this guy Fornoyman
たぶん私はこの男のことを考えるでしょう フォーノイマン
You can't finish the story about Fornoyman
フォーノイマンの話を終わらせることはできない
he is a very interesting person
彼はとても興味深い人です
because he is so famous
彼はとても有名なので
Inventing new things all the time
常に新しいものを発明する
so he didn't win any awards
だから彼は何の賞も受賞しなかった
ok
Ok
one of his most famous examples
彼の最も有名な例の一つ
of course that means
もちろんそれは意味します
if you have heard
聞いたことがあるなら
The so-called bland project H Bomb
いわゆる当たり障りのない水爆プロジェクト
he is a very important person
彼はとても大切な人です
ok
Ok
He's in a light plan
彼は軽い計画を立てている
Fornoyman he probably played
彼はおそらくプレーしたであろうフォーノイマン
very important role
とても重要な役割
Then what
じゃあ何
Does he have anything to do with statistics?
彼は統計と何か関係がありますか?
I need you to check his academic background
彼の学歴を調べてほしい
Of course he's had some experience with statistics.
もちろん、彼には統計に関する経験があります。
because he's a mathematician at heart
彼は根っからの数学者だから
There must be a problem with statistics
統計に問題があるに違いない
So you're saying what does he have to do with game theory?
つまり、彼はゲーム理論と何の関係があると言っているのでしょうか？
should say so
そう言うべきだ
If we take Fornoyman's name off
フォーノイマンの名前を外したら
no light in game
ゲーム内に光がありません
so he's so funny
だから彼はとても面白いです
Because he is in many fields
色々な分野で活躍されているので、
he is the founder
彼は創設者です
But what?
でも何？
because of him
彼のせいで
The real interest is actually mathematics itself
本当の興味は実は数学そのものなのです
So like Game Theory for him
彼にとってはゲーム理論のようなものです
just a novel
ただの小説
He went to write a book when he wrote about it
彼はそれについて書いたときに本を書きに行った
It has something to do with the game we are talking about today.
それは今日話しているゲームと関係があります。
Fornoiman
フォルノイマン
That's why he died young
それが彼が若くして亡くなった理由です
when i died
私が死んだとき
Why
なぜ
Because he participated in the light program
ライトプログラムに参加したため
so at that time
だからその時は
Scientists of about the same generation as him
彼とほぼ同世代の科学者
probably die earlier
大概都比較早死
I didn't have that feeling at that time
当時はそんな気持ちなかったけど
It means that you participate in the light program
ライトプログラムに参加していることを意味します
It's actually a very dangerous thing
実はとても危険なことなんです
so he died early
だから彼は早く亡くなった
OK so Fornoyman
はい、それではフォーノイマン
then we have to look through him
それなら私たちは彼を通して調べなければなりません
Are these three things related?
この３つは関連しているのでしょうか？
So I asked a question below
そこで以下に質問してみました
that is
あれは
statistics
統計
Match
マッチ
politics
政治
just rely on such a person
そんな人に頼るだけ
can we link it together?
一緒にリンクしてもいいですか？
the answer is of course no
答えはもちろんノーです
because this is a very interesting person
この人はとても面白い人なので
we can connect it
私たちはそれを接続することができます
Then we will now look at the relationship between these three
では、この３つの関係を見てみましょう
i think it should
そうすべきだと思います
From the next point of view
次の視点から
where does statistics come from
統計はどこから来たのか
we want to ask a historic question
私たちは歴史的な質問をしたいのです
I deliberately inserted the answer first
意図的に答えを最初に挿入しました
OK what is the answer
OK、答えは何ですか
take a look
見てください
let me ask you a question first
まず質問させてください
what is statistics in english
統計って英語でなんて言うの？
you know
ほら
Statistics in English is statistics
統計学は英語でstatisticsです。
Have you ever thought
今まで考えたことがありますか
What does this statistics mean
この統計は何を意味するのか
this word is very long
この言葉はとても長いです
and very convoluted
そして非常に複雑です
right
右
it's there
それはそこにあります
The current Latin is called statisticoon
現在のラテン語は statisticoon と呼ばれています
it's the same
それは同じだ
from statistics
統計から
extend out
伸ばす
have you ever thought
考えたことはありますか
Why is it called statistics
なぜ統計と呼ばれるのか
ok now tell everyone
よし、今度はみんなに教えて
because it's math for politics
それは政治のための数学だから
So statistics
つまり統計
is to measure your country
あなたの国を測ることです
so it's political science
だからそれは政治学だ
from political science
政治学から
OK, many people think that
そうですね、多くの人がそう思います
how could this be
これはどうやってできるの
we hear now
今聞いています
Statistics seem to be
統計ではこうなるようです
what mathematicians are doing
数学者は何をしているのか
How to start with political science
政治学を始めるには
have you ever thought about this
これについて考えたことがありますか
Look at the book below that was published in 1663
1663 年に出版された以下の本を見てください。
就是The Nature and Political Observations upon the Bill of Mortality
即ち死亡法案の性質と政治的見解
Its author is called John Grunt
著者はジョン・グラントといいます
Published in 1663
1663 年に出版
This is probably the first
おそらくこれが最初です
The first book compares contemporary
最初の本は現代を比較します
The more modern concept of so-called statistics
いわゆる統計のより現代的な概念
wrote it out
それを書き出しました
what does it talk about
それは何について話しますか
it's about nature and politics
それは自然と政治に関するものです
Mortality from the point of view of nature and politics
自然と政治の観点から見た死亡率
If you do demography or statistics
人口統計や統計を行う場合
maybe you should know
たぶんあなたは知っておくべきです
John Grunt is very important
ジョン・グラントは非常に重要です
We can imagine that in 1663 in
1663 年を想像できます。
when is china
中国はいつですか
Late Ming Dynasty Early Qing Dynasty
明代後期 清代初期
is there such a person
そんな人はいますか
seems difficult
難しそうです
but he has written a
しかし彼はこう書いている
everyone noticed
誰もが気づいた
One of his keywords is Political
彼のキーワードの一つは「政治」
so it becomes
そうなります
The word statistics at the beginning
冒頭の統計という言葉
originally political science
もともとは政治学
then the first
それから最初の
Comparing modern approaches to writing statistics
統計を書くための最新のアプローチの比較
This book of statistics
この統計の本は
It has a word called Protocolic
プロトコリックという言葉があります
So stop saying that political science is not science
だから政治学は科学ではないなんて言うのはやめよう
because statistics comes before all science
なぜなら統計はあらゆる科学よりも優先されるからです
it starts with political science
それは政治学から始まります
I'm really kidding
本当に冗談だよ
I said statistics
統計って言いました
we all know now
今では誰もが知っています
The most basic concept of statistics is that
統計の最も基本的な概念は次のとおりです。
you have a mother
あなたには母親がいます
right, there is a mother body
そう、母体があるのです
Then I sampled from the matrix
次に、マトリックスからサンプリングしました
Then I'm going to look at the sampling process
次に、サンプリングプロセスを見ていきます
is it random
ランダムですか
So I just take a thousand more samples
それで、さらに 1,000 個のサンプルを採取するだけです
I can infer
推測できます
Infer what the mother's body is likely to be like
母親の体がどのようになっているかを推測する
You may have thought of one thing
あなたは一つのことを考えたことがあるかもしれません
Where was statistics first used?
統計が最初に使用されたのはどこですか?
population
人口
what is population in english
人口って英語でなんて言うの？
It's called Population
それは人口と呼ばれます
Do you understand?
わかりますか？
That is to say, we now say that the matrix
つまり、行列は次のようになります。
Actually sorry to say
本当に申し訳ありませんが
It originally meant population
元々は人口を意味していた
then i will tell you a story
それから私はあなたに話をします
that is
あれは
Let me tell you one
先講一個
In fact, there is no concrete evidence to show the story
実際、この話を示す具体的な証拠はありません
but i think it should be like that
でもそうあるべきだと思う
think about it
考えてみてください
in the fifteenth and sixteenth centuries
15世紀と16世紀に
fifteenth and sixteenth centuries
十五十六世紀
who is interested in that
誰がそれに興味がありますか
who has that resource
誰がそのリソースを持っているか
To find out how many people he managed
彼が何人の人を管理していたのかを知るために
king
王
Then what
じゃあ何
he will want to say
彼は言い​​たいだろう
How can I use the lowest cost
どうすれば最安で利用できるか
minimum cost
最低コスト
To know how many people I have here
ここに何人いるのか知りたい
what to do
何をすべきか
to war
戦争へ
know what i mean
わかる
because you look like
あなたは次のように見えるから
Europe in the fifteenth and sixteenth centuries
15世紀から16世紀のヨーロッパ
basically in the
基本的には
in a state of war
戦争状態にある
then you can think of one thing
それなら一つ考えられることがある
that is to say this thing
つまりこのことを言うのです
a king
王様
He can know how many people he has
彼は自分が何人いるかを知ることができる
can fight
戦える
how much tax can he collect
彼はいくらの税金を徴収できるだろうか
so as not to cause riots
暴動を起こさないように
That way he's more likely to win
そうすれば彼は勝つ可能性が高くなります
So he hates war
だから彼は戦争が嫌いだ
so you know what to say
だから何を言えばいいかわかるでしょう
The concept of statistics
統計の概念
In fact, he is in the modern country
実は彼は現代の国にいるのです
in the process of forming
形成の過程で
a very strong false
非常に強い虚偽
that is, if I could know
つまり、私が知ることができたなら
if i could know
もし知ることができたら
what method do i use
どのような方法を使用しますか
can maximize my benefits
私の利益を最大限に高めることができます
I have a chance to win
勝つチャンスはある
So you can immediately imagine a thing
だからすぐに想像できる
That is to say, what do these kings do?
つまり、これらの王たちは何をしているのでしょうか？
i'm imagining
私は想像しています
Maybe this existed in some time and space very early
おそらくこれは非常に早い時期と空間に存在していました
What he does is actually very simple
彼がやっていることは実際には非常に単純です
For example, I brought my Dacheng
たとえば、私は大成を持ってきました
Find 20 Dacheng
大成を20個見つける
He said you should at least go now
彼は少なくとも今は行くべきだと言いました
to my territory to see
私の領土に行って見てください
what to see
何を見てください
how many people do you see
何人見えますか
And you can't two people go to the same place
そして二人で同じ場所に行くことはできない
right he might have a map over here
そう、彼はここに地図を持っているかもしれない
when the time comes you will look around
時間が来たら周りを見回すだろう
Then you take what you see
それからあなたは見たものを受け取ります
come back and talk to me
戻ってきて私に話してください
That process is called random sampling
そのプロセスはランダムサンプリングと呼ばれます
OK, so random sampling means
OK、ランダムサンプリングということは、
You see the population I rule
私が統治する人口がわかります
This is called the motif
これをモチーフといいます
OK then you sample it yourself
OK、それなら自分でサンプリングしてください
come back and report to me
戻ってきて私に報告してください
the one who can do it
それができる人
He actually has a higher chance of winning.
実際には彼の方が勝つ可能性が高い。
OK so everyone understands
OK、みんなは理解しています
That is to say, statistics, he actually
つまり、統計、彼は実際に
His origin is not mysterious at all
彼の出自は全く謎ではない
He was measuring your territory
彼はあなたの領域を測定していました
OK
OK
let me say it again by the way
ちなみにもう一度言わせてください
Let's talk about that later
それについては後で話しましょう
John Grunt's story
ジョン・グラントの物語
the book he wrote
彼が書いた本
He is studying the death of the population of London
彼はロンドンの人口の死を研究している
That's because there was a very important issue happening in London at the time.
それは、当時ロンドンで非常に重要な問題が起こっていたからです。
called meaning
意味と呼ばれる
Interested
興味がある
So he called Protocol Observations
そこで彼はプロトコル・オブザベーションズに電話をかけた
Which means you have to give him a political observation
つまり、彼に政治的見解を与える必要がある
Why
なぜ
Because I was very interested in such research at the time
当時私はそのような研究に非常に興味を持っていたので、
because you think about being a king
あなたは王になることを考えているから
He's actually in Chouse II
彼は実際にはChouse IIにいます
Huse II
ちょうせ いい
That British history itself is very complicated
イギリスの歴史自体が非常に複雑であること
But the king of England at that time was called Chouse II
しかし、当時のイングランド国王はチョース2世と呼ばれていました。
II
二世
Then there is a great need for someone to do this kind of research
したがって、この種の研究を行う人が非常に必要です
Why
なぜ
Because mortality is probably the foundation of a regime
死亡率はおそらく体制の基盤だから
if your rule
あなたのルールなら
your population is dead
あなたの人口は死んでいます
what do you rule
あなたは何を統治しますか
so the first thing he does
それで彼が最初にすることは
Is it possible to pass through
通り抜けることは可能ですか
Such research to understand why people die
人がなぜ死ぬのかを理解するための研究
Or these British subjects below us
あるいは我々の下にいる英国臣民たち
What is the average life expectancy
平均寿命はどれくらいですか
So he must be using statistics
だから彼は統計を使っているに違いない
He must be using statistics
彼は統計を使っているに違いない
and then tell my readers to say
そして読者にこう言うように伝えてください
How much is our mortality rate the first
まず私たちの死亡率はどれくらいですか
For example, how many people in a thousand people will die?
たとえば、1000人中何人が亡くなるでしょうか？
for what reason
いかなる理由で
And then of course this involves his investigation.
そしてもちろん、これには彼の調査が含まれます。
Then I can also describe
それなら私も説明できます
For example, the average population of the city of London at that time
たとえば、当時のロンドン市の平均人口は
What is the life expectancy
平均余命はどれくらいですか
So this is a very important work
ということで、とても大切な作業です
downground
地下
That
それか
Of course later
もちろん後ほど
This matter was followed by other scholars.
この件については他の学者も追随した。
The statistics we now know better
私たちが今よく知っている統計
Actually it was later
実はもっと後だった
But he started out to find out where you rule
でも彼はあなたがどこを支配しているかを調べ始めました
so the other day i heard that kurpi
それで先日、クルピのことを聞きました
He said something that I found quite interesting
彼は私がとても興味深いと思ったことを言いました
He said there would be no governance without statistics
彼は統計がなければガバナンスは存在しないと述べた
nothing wrong
何も間違っていません
because he is a doctor
彼は医者だから
statistics are important
統計は重要です
Like you don't even know you're in
自分がそこにいることにさえ気づいていないかのように
rule where
どこでルールを決める
You don't understand how you manage it
あなたはそれをどのように管理するのか理解していません
there's nothing wrong with that
それは何も問題ありません
Well, then of course it means
まあ、それなら当然ということですが、
We are more impressed by these
私たちはこれらにさらに感銘を受けています
Theoretical development with statistics
統計を使った理論開発
Of course the mathematicians are starting to creep in
もちろん数学者も忍び込み始めている
For example, there are quite a few famous people mentioned here.
たとえば、ここにはかなりの数の有名人が言及されています。
For example, one of the most important theories
たとえば、最も重要な理論の 1 つは、
Chance of course
もちろんチャンス
probability
確率
Probability is of course a mathematical concept
確率はもちろん数学的な概念です
But you see these people are quite famous
でも、この人たちはかなり有名だということがわかりますね
For example, Baskar and Xianglan
例えばバスカルとシャンラン
That's the one
それだ
Do you know, Ferma?
知っていますか、フェルマ？
should have listened
聞くべきだった
Is there a math department here?
ここに数学部はありますか?
Institute of Mathematics
数学研究所
dare not speak
あえて話さないでください
OK OK
はいはい
ferma is famous
フェルマは有名です
Of course these are mathematicians
もちろん彼らは数学者です
Then what
じゃあ何
Look at that Gauss again
もう一度あのガウスを見てください
Namely CF Gauss 1794
つまりCFガウス1794
that his
それは彼の
knowledge of statistics
統計の知識
That is to say, he builds on a foundation
つまり、基礎の上に築いていくのです
He said
彼は言った
when people have to decide
人々が決断しなければならないとき
must face uncertainty
不確実性に直面しなければならない
So we're going to find a
そこで、
The most rational decision-making model
最も合理的な意思決定モデル
is to minimize
最小限にすることです
face uncertainty
不確実性に直面する
This is a fundamental of statistics
これは統計学の基本です
this concept
このコンセプト
That is to say, there must be errors in our statistics.
つまり、統計には必ず誤差が含まれます。
If you see a paper next time
今度紙を見たら
It's my sampling with no error at all
これは私のサンプリングであり、まったくエラーはありません
don't you believe
信じませんか
ok statistics biggest job
オーケー、統計最大の仕事
is to minimize our error
私たちのエラーを最小限に抑えることです
but there must be errors
しかし間違いがあるはずです
Okay, let's take a look at this guy first.
さて、まずはこの男を見てみましょう。
This is John Brown
こちらはジョン・ブラウンです
this is a very interesting person
この人はとても興味深い人です
He is a Fellow of the Royal Society
彼は王立協会のフェローです
He had the Royal Society
彼には王立協会があった
That's why he wants to be an academician
だからこそ彼は学者になりたいのです
This thing is taken by many other
これは他の多くの人が取り上げています
Fellows of the Royal Society object
王立協会のフェローが反対
Why
なぜ
Have you ever thought about this question
この質問について考えたことがありますか
please teach me
教えて下さい
why do you think he was opposed
なぜ彼は反対されたと思いますか
you don't know him well
あなたは彼のことをよく知りません
you say you don't know
あなたは知らないと言います
you say you say
あなたは言う、あなたは言う
not yet
まだ
Only he will have statistics in the future
将来的には彼だけが統計を得るでしょう
no that book sold well
いいえ、その本はよく売れました
for what reason
いかなる理由で
Have you ever thought about this question
この質問について考えたことがありますか
you hurry up
急いでください
so and so
まだまだ
just speak louder
もっと大きな声で話してください
ok then we should find out
わかった、じゃあ調べてみよう
What were the fellows of the Royal Society doing at the time?
王立協会の仲間たちは当時何をしていましたか?
I don't have an answer to this right now
今のところこれに対する答えはありません
I don't know. Going to investigate
わかりません。調査してみます
out of line
ラインから外れている
very good
とても良い
This is a political interpretation
これは政治的な解釈です
is there any other explanation
他に説明はありますか
It's about Newton
ニュートンのことだよ
should be ok
大丈夫なはず
but this is fun
でもこれは楽しいです
Newton's era should be about the same as his
ニュートンの時代は彼の時代とほぼ同じはずだ
Yes, but Newton, the founder of the Royal Society, was a little bit older than him.
はい、しかし王立協会の創設者であるニュートンは彼より少し年上でした。
is there any other answer
他に答えはありますか
this is very interesting
これはとても興味深いです
The first person to write a book on statistics
統計に関する本を初めて書いた人
Why him? Will he object to his entry into the Royal Society?
なぜ彼が? 彼は王立協会への入会に反対するでしょうか?
Why did he enter the Royal Society?
なぜ彼は王立協会に入ったのでしょうか？
yes
はい
he and he is not considered scientific
彼も彼も科学的とはみなされていない
In fact, he also saw that you had a Publication at that time.
実際、彼はその時点であなたが出版物を持っていることにも気づきました。
Right? People with good publications are more likely to
そうですか? 優れた出版物を持っている人は、
then you are probably right
それならあなたはおそらく正しい
Do you know what his identity is?
彼の正体が何なのか知っていますか？
Soldiers, at that time many people were called Captain
兵士、当時は大尉と呼ばれる人が多かった
Below are some Captains
以下はキャプテンの一部です
And then it's over, he's an interesting identity.
それで終わりだ、彼は興味深い人物だ。
he is in the sales department
彼は営業部にいます
Because their family moved to London later
彼らの家族は後にロンドンに移住したため、
His father is a businessman
彼の父親は実業家です
That is to say, if you want to make clothes, you need to find his father.
つまり、服を作りたければ、父親を探さなければなりません。
so he is a businessman
だから彼はビジネスマンです
know what i mean
わかる
Then he didn't have any high education
それから彼は高学歴ではなかった
that's interesting that is to say
それは面白いということです
He certainly inherited his father's trade
彼は確かに父親の商売を引き継いだ
He is also a salesman
彼は販売員でもあります
because we think he's weird
私たちは彼が変だと思うから
I want to ask Mr. Wang Hu about this
このことについて王胡さんに聞きたいのですが
Is it possible that such a person would come out in China at that time?
当時の中国にそんな人物が出てくる可能性はあるでしょうか？
unlikely right
正しくない
Very difficult
非常に難しい
Even in the UK, he is opposed by many people
イギリスでも彼は多くの人から反対されている
That is to say, how can a businessman enter the Royal Academy?
つまり、ビジネスマンがどうやって王立アカデミーに入学できるのでしょうか？
I don't know that our traditional Chinese medicine hospital is of course much better now.
もちろん、私たちの漢方病院が現在より良くなっているのかどうかはわかりません。
But I don't know why the British Royal Academy at that time had such
しかし、当時の英国王立アカデミーがなぜそのようなものを持っていたのかはわかりません。
He was actually discriminated against, simply put, discriminated against
彼は実際に差別されていた、簡単に言えば、差別されていた
Then a friend just mentioned why he went in later, do you know?
それから、友人がなぜ後で入ったのかについて話しました、知っていますか？
I don't know about this, I don't have any evidence, I can't just talk about it
これについては分かりません、証拠もないので簡単に話すことはできません
but that book is selling well
でもその本はよく売れています
It is because the current Chos'a second recommended him to say
それはチョスア二世が彼にこう勧めたからである。
you want to let him in
あなたは彼を中に入れたいのですか
know what i mean
わかる
So it's not that he doesn't fit in with the Dao, but he fits in with the Dao
つまり、彼は道に適合しないのではなく、道に適合するのです。
This is good, politics is always there
これはいいことだ、政治はいつでもそこにある
That is to say, your relationship with the leader actually has a little influence.
つまり、リーダーとの関係は実際には少し影響するということです
So this is a pretty interesting story
それで、これはかなり興味深い話です
That is to say, we look at it from the perspective of historical eyes
つまり、歴史的な目で見るということです。
The development of fellow economics, of course he has his
仲間の経済学の発展、もちろん彼には彼のものがあります
The actual demand is quite strong
実際の需要はかなり強い
Then we saw that the word classmate was meant to measure your country
それから、クラスメートという言葉があなたの国を表すことを意味していることがわかりました
And then the first statistics textbook was kind of like this thing
そして最初の統計の教科書はこんな感じでした
In fact, he was talking about politics.
実際、彼は政治について話していました。
He talks about Mortality
他講Motality
If he wants to enter, the Huang Family Academy will not be able to enter.
彼が入学したければ、黄家学院には入学できない。
But because Chalster II appreciates his
しかし、チャルスター2世は彼のことを高く評価しているので、
That is to say, you must let him in, and he will go in.
つまり、あなたが彼を中に入れなければなりません、そうすれば彼は入るでしょう。
So of course he has a little influence on the later research
もちろん、彼は後の研究に多少の影響を与えています
We are now reading about the life cycle
私たちは今ライフサイクルについて読んでいます
should read this guy
この人を読むべきだ
But his real identity is a cloth seller
しかし彼の正体は布販売者。
OK so I think it's a funny thing
そうですね、それは面白いことだと思います
Let's look at this question again
もう一度この質問を見てみましょう
Now let's talk about these three things separately.
それでは、これら 3 つのことについて個別に説明しましょう。
that's next
それは次です
We want to say that this is what statistics look like
統計とはこういうものだと私たちは言いたいのです
What is the so-called game?
いわゆるゲームとは何ですか？
In fact, the game theory should not be complicated
実際、ゲーム理論は複雑であってはなりません
'Cause we're playing games every day
私たちは毎日ゲームをしているから
OK, for example, if you are older, you can play mahjong
OK、たとえば、年上の人なら麻雀をしてもいいでしょう。
play poker
ポーカーをする
the younger man
若い男
Maybe as soon as December 31st someone wants to play a board game
おそらく12月31日には誰かがボードゲームをプレイしたいと思うでしょう
right
右
human beings as long as they live
人間は生きている限り
Everyone wants to play some games
誰もがいくつかのゲームをプレイしたいと考えています
In fact, it is called Game Theory, which means game theory.
実際にはゲーム理論と呼ばれ、ゲーム理論を意味します。
It is more clearly called Spill Theory in German
ドイツ語では、より明確に「流出理論」と呼ばれます。
Spill means to play
スピルとは「遊ぶ」という意味です
So it's not so mysterious
だからそこまで神秘的じゃないよ
So we think of it ourselves as if
だから私たちはそれを次のように考えます
like something we don't understand
私たちには理解できないもののように
It's not that mysterious
そんなに神秘的じゃないよ
it means to say
それは言うことを意味します
when we make a decision
私たちが決断を下すとき
If I have several options to choose from
いくつかの選択肢がある場合
why i choose this method
なぜこの方法を選んだのか
unselective method
不選別的方法
isn't it simple
単純ではないですか
now game theory
今はゲーム理論
The funniest thing about it is
一番面白いのは、
When I'm thinking about what method I'm going to use
どのような方法でやろうかと考えたとき
You should also consider what other people are thinking
他の人が何を考えているかも考慮する必要があります
right
右
Because a really good player
本当に良い選手なので
You must have thought of this
あなたはこれを考えたはずです
That is to say, if I play this card now
つまり、今このカードをプレイすると、
then will you follow
それではフォローしますか
or you will have better cards
そうしないともっと良いカードが手に入ります
right
右
People who are more good at playing should think about this.
演奏が上手な人はこれを考えてみてください。
Then I often discuss with my mother
それから母とよく話し合います
playing mahjong
麻雀をする
I feel really great
本当に素晴らしい気分です
she is very old
彼女はとても年をとっている
but still played well
それでもよくプレーした
She said you really have to know how to play mahjong
彼女は麻雀の打ち方を本当に知らなければならないと言いました
You must know what the other three are thinking
他の3人が何を考えているか分かるはずだ
or you will lose
そうしないと負けてしまいます
this is really awesome
これは本当に素晴らしいです
that means
つまり
a person who is actually making decisions
実際に意思決定を行っている人
He not only has to consider his own interests
彼は自分の利益だけを考慮しなければならないだけではありません
consider his own position
自分の立場を考える
Not only should he consider
彼は考慮すべきであるだけでなく、
What kind of decision is better for him
どのような決断が彼にとって良いのか
His considerations should include what others are thinking
彼の考慮事項には、他の人が考えていることも含まれている必要があります
so everyone can understand
誰もが理解できるように
So when it comes to Game Theory
ゲーム理論に関して言えば、
It is actually a core concept
それは実際には核となる概念です
called Common Knowledge
常識と呼ばれる
is the consensus
はコンセンサスです
what is consensus
コンセンサスとは何ですか
it's me thinking what are you thinking
それは私が考えていることです、あなたは何を考えていますか
I know what you're thinking about me
あなたが私について何を考えているか知っています
So when I'm thinking about what you're thinking
だから私があなたが考えていることを考えているとき
i know you know
私は知っています、あなたは知っています
i know what you're thinking
あなたが何を考えているか知っています
know what i mean
わかる
You know what I'm talking about when you do this
これをやると私が何を言っているかわかるでしょう
but it means
しかし、それは意味します
when i was thinking what is the best solution
何が最善の解決策なのか考えたとき
I must take into account
考慮しなければなりません
What are others thinking about this solution?
この解決策について他の人はどう考えていますか?
Well, this is actually what we do in our daily life.
まあ、これは実際に私たちが日常生活で行っていることです。
a frequently encountered situation
よく遭遇する状況
Is this good?
これでいいですか？
OK, for example, during the election
たとえば、選挙期間中に
Do you think typing this negative text now
今この否定的なテキストを入力すると思いますか
or he is helpful to you
あるいは彼はあなたの役に立ちます
Then you send negative WeChat
次に、否定的な WeChat を送信します
He must have thought of how the other party would fight back.
相手がどう反撃するか考えたのだろう。
is when you take everything into consideration
すべてを考慮したときです
Maybe that's a thing they call equilibrium
それが均衡というものなのかもしれない
so
それで
Strategy跟calculation
戦略計算
This thing was meant to be put together
これはまとめるつもりだったんだ
Then I want to remind you one word
それから、一つだけ思い出させていただきたいのですが、
called Strategy
戦略と呼ばれる
OK because when we say
OK、なぜなら私たちが言うとき
when we are playing a game
ゲームをするとき
The method I choose is called Strategy
私が選んだ方法は戦略と呼ばれます
According to Julien
ジュリアンによると
what does he call strategy
彼は戦略を何と呼んでいますか
what is his name
彼の名前は
I remember he seemed to call it a strategy or a strategy
彼はそれを戦略とか戦略とか呼んでいるようだったのを覚えている
His is Chao Abe's three strategies
これが安倍チャオの3つの戦略だ
Anyway
ともかく
what
何
ok ok
OK
In fact, his English is Strategy
実際、彼の英語は戦略です
Strategy is an interesting concept
戦略とは興味深い概念です
Let's say I'm telling you now
たとえば、今教えてください
The game is studying Strategy
ゲームは戦略を勉強しています
That is to say, I know several strategies
つまり、いくつかの戦略を知っています
English is called strategy
英語は戦略と呼ばれます
Actually, the first thing you think of is political science.
実際、最初に思いつくのは政治学です。
right
右
The most care in political science is strategy
政治学で最も注意すべきことは戦略です
Economics is not very good at speaking this word
経済学はこの言葉を話すのが苦手です
But one of the almost central problems of political science is that
しかし、政治学のほぼ中心的な問題の 1 つは、
where is your strategy
あなたの戦略はどこにありますか
You should now be able to find some links
これで、いくつかのリンクが見つかるはずです
That is to say, why was there statistics in the first place?
つまり、そもそもなぜ統計が存在したのかということです。
Because national defense requires war
国防には戦争が必要だから
how do you win the war
どうやって戦争に勝つのですか
In addition to your data to be correct
正しいデータに加えて
You also need to know what the other party is going to do
相手が何をしようとしているのかも知る必要があります
that's called strategy
それは戦略と呼ばれます
so early on
とても早い段階で
these things just go together
これらはただ一緒に起こる
good
良い
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
So when it comes to this so-called game theory
つまり、このいわゆるゲーム理論に関して言えば、
i want to mention him a little bit
彼のことについて少し触れたいと思います
when we just ate
私たちがちょうど食べたとき
Still talking to the vice president about this person
この人物について今も副大統領と話し合っている
Called Thibis Nash
ティビス・ナッシュと呼ばれる
On the left is when he was younger
左が若い頃
On the right is when he won the award
右は受賞時のもの
But during this time
しかしこの間、
The vice president should be invited to introduce him
副大統領を紹介するために招待されるべきである
Ask Nash to meet them
ナッシュに会うように頼む
should have met
会うべきだった
his story is very very wonderful
彼の話はとてもとても素晴らしいです
If you are interested
もし興味があれば
you can go to him
彼のところに行ってもいいよ
It should be someone else helped him write the album
誰かが彼のために書いたアルバムであるべきだ
It's called A Beautiful Mind
それはビューティフル・マインドと呼ばれています
beautiful mind
ビューティフル・マインド
very well written
とてもよく書かれています
what kind of man would nash be
ナッシュはどんな男だろう
who we are reading the innings of now
私たちが今ゲームを読んでいるのは誰ですか
There's probably no way you don't know Nash's name.
ナッシュという名前を知らないはずがないでしょう
Why
なぜ
Because your equilibrium is called Nash
あなたの平衡状態はナッシュと呼ばれているからです
if you take Nash off
ナッシュを脱がせたら
you don't know what you're doing
あなたは自分が何をしているのか分かりません
So now we are looking for something every day
だから今私たちは毎日何かを探しています
Called Nash Junker
ナッシュ・ユンカーと呼ばれる
Nash means Nash
ナッシュとはナッシュのことです
Then I remember when I was learning the game
それから私はゲームを学んでいたときのことを思い出しました
i asked my boss
私は上司に尋ねました
When did Jiang Nash die?
ジャン・ナッシュはいつ亡くなったのですか?
He said there is no death
彼は死はないと言った
why didn't he write paper
なぜ彼は論文を書かなかったのか
Shouldn't he write a lot of papers?
彼はたくさん論文を書くべきではないでしょうか？
Then you go to see his doctoral dissertation
それから彼の博士論文を見に行きます
He originally wrote his doctoral dissertation
彼は最初に博士論文を書きました
Hearing and writing three pages
3 ページを聞いて書く
Later he was too embarrassed to tell him
後で彼は恥ずかしくて彼に話しました
don't just write three pages
3ページだけ書くのではなく
Later he wrote him in twenty-one pages
その後、彼は21ページにわたって彼に手紙を書いた
You can still download now
今でもダウンロードできます
maybe hit his name
もしかしたら彼の名前がヒットするかもしれない
It should be possible to connect to download his doctoral thesis
博士論文をダウンロードするために接続できるはずです
That doctoral dissertation is very well written
その博士論文は非常によく書かれています
his most important contribution
彼の最も重要な貢献
The so-called Naschic Lubeum
所謂的Naschic Lubeum
Naschic Lincoln
ナシック・リンカーン
from his doctoral dissertation
彼の博士論文から
OK, that's John Nash.
はい、ジョン・ナッシュです。
himself his story is full of drama
彼自身、彼の物語はドラマに満ちている
when he was already very famous
彼がすでにとても有名だったとき
After about 30 years old
30歳くらいから
He has Skytophrenia
彼はスカイトフレニアを患っている
just have schizophrenia
ただ統合失調症を患っているだけ
OK, of course I heard that Princeden is very nice to him.
もちろん、プリンスデンは彼にとても親切だと聞いています。
So he was in Princeden for a long time
それで彼は長い間プリンスデンにいた
In 1994, he was to be awarded the Norbert Prize in Economics
1994年に彼はノーバート経済学賞を受賞する予定だった
see how long it takes
どれくらい時間がかかるか見てみましょう
so he is a very important person
だから彼はとても大切な人です
So why is John Nash so important?
では、なぜジョン・ナッシュがそれほど重要なのでしょうか?
he has a little story
彼にはちょっとした話がある
That is to say, the person he most admires
つまり、彼が最も尊敬する人
It's the first photo
最初の写真です
Fornoiman
フォルノイマン
Why
なぜ
because Fornoyman was in Princeden at the time
フォーノイマンもプリンスデンにいたから
Institute for Advanced Study
高等研究院
So he always wanted to
それで彼はいつもそうしたいと思っていました
The great John Fornoyman had an impression of him
偉大なジョン・フォーノイマンは彼に印象を残した
because he's just a young guy
彼はただの若い男だから
go to doctoral class
博士課程に行く
he knows why
彼はその理由を知っています
Why did he choose Prince instead of Harvard?
なぜ彼はハーバード大学ではなくプリンスを選んだのでしょうか?
'Cause Prince's got these freaks over there
プリンスには変人たちがいるから
Einstein that Fernoyman
アインシュタインとファーノイマン
It's these freaks from Europe
ヨーロッパから来た変人たちだよ
i just forgot to say
ただ言い忘れただけです
That is to say, Jiang Fernoyman
つまり、ジャン・ファーノイマン
He is a Hungarian Jew
彼はハンガリー系ユダヤ人です
he is complicated
彼は複雑だ
not very complicated
それほど複雑ではありません
Said his family affairs are complicated
彼の家庭事情は複雑だという
what game did he play when he was a kid
彼は子供の頃どんなゲームをしましたか
his daddy would put his daddy as a banker
彼の父親は彼の父親を銀行家にするだろう
just call him
彼に電話してください
Come now you make a game for
さあ、あなたはゲームを作ります
my guest see
私のゲストが見てください
Come on, here is a phone book, right?
さあ、ここに電話帳がありますよね？
then you start watching now
それなら今から見始めてください
Watch it, cover it up
見てください、隠蔽してください
Come on, you recite their phone numbers
さあ、彼らの電話番号を暗唱してください
I think it's best not to let my kids play this kind of game
自分の子供にはこの種のゲームをさせない方が良いと思います
scary
怖い
he is a genius
彼は天才です
Then for Jiang Nash to let
次に、ジャン・ナッシュに任せます。
that's what they call
それを彼らはそう呼んでいます
It just came to my mind
ふと思いついたのですが
That is to say, in order to impress Jiang Fernoyman
つまり、ジャン・ファーノイマンに好印象を与えるために
He went to discuss math problems with him
彼は数学の問題について話し合うために行った
but heard
でも聞いた
I heard that Jiang Fernoyman could not bear to dump him
ジャン・ファーノイマンは彼を捨てるのが耐えられなかったと聞いた
He was greatly stimulated
彼はとても刺激を受けました
I did the game before and I did the game
前にもゲームをやったし、またゲームもやった
So he later wrote his national books
それで彼は後に全国的な本を書きました
that this is a short story
これは短編小説だということ
But I know that between these mathematicians
しかし、私はこれらの数学者の間でそれを知っています
they have some really weird connections
彼らには本当に奇妙なつながりがある
But then of course because he wrote
しかし、もちろん、彼が書いたので、
The so-called National Collibion
いわゆる国家衝突
become famous
有名になる
OK so famous we don't even know where he is
OK、あまりにも有名なので、彼がどこにいるのかさえわかりません
but he is very important
しかし彼はとても重要です
But certainly no John Nash without Fanolimne
しかし、ファノリムネのいないジョン・ナッシュは確かに存在しない
They are actually linked
それらは実際にリンクされています
Well this is John Nash
さて、こちらはジョン・ナッシュです
Then let's talk a little bit about the last topic.
それでは、最後のトピックについて少しお話しましょう。
The so-called political science in the institute
研究所におけるいわゆる政治学
Now back to the core question of political science
さて、政治学の核心的な問題に戻りましょう
The core problem is probably Power
中心的な問題はおそらく電源です
Power
力
But how many words are there that are very similar to Power?
しかし、「Power」によく似た単語はどれくらいあるでしょうか?
Do you want to talk about it here?
ここでそれについて話したいですか？
Closer to Power
権力に近づく
related to power
権力に関係する
Authority
権限
authority power
権威権力
that is not that force this force
それはその力ではありません、この力は
is the power of that power it does not
それはその力の力ではありません
ok then let me tell you
わかりました、それでは教えてください
Authority it is a very interesting state
権威は非常に興味深い状態です
its essence is violence
その本質は暴力である
what is violence
暴力とは何ですか
It's just that I can make you not want to do this thing
ただ、私はあなたがこのことをしたくないようにすることができます
I must let you do this
これはあなたにやらせなければなりません
if you don't want to
したくない場合は
I can restrict your freedom
私はあなたの自由を制限することができます
To put it bluntly, I can lock you up
はっきり言って、君を閉じ込めてもいいよ
that's what it means
それが意味です
OK, of course I can use many other methods
もちろん、他の多くの方法も使用できます
to restrict you from doing something
あなたが何かをするのを制限する
So it's essentially a violence
つまり本質的には暴力だ
So its violence means
つまり、その暴力が意味するのは、
I know you really don't want to do such a thing
本当はそんなことしたくないのはわかってるよ
But I force you to do such a thing
でも私はあなたにそんなことを強要する
Okay, so why can Authority be compared with violence?
では、なぜ権威が暴力と比較されるのでしょうか?
Because there is a process in it
そこには過程があるから
OK it's a power
オーケー、それは力だ
what is power
力とは何ですか
power and the force that general economists talk about
一般経済学者が語る権力と力
a little different
少し違う
power means
力の意味
if i say now to you
今あなたに言ったら
If I don't have power for you
もし私にあなたの力がなかったら
I'm not sure if you'll listen to me
私の言うことを聞いてもらえるか分かりません
so it has a mandatory meaning
したがって、それは必須の意味を持っています
power means mandatory
権力とは強制力を意味します
so its core
だからその核心
Because it is essentially relying on violence
本質的に暴力に頼っているから
so it will have power
だから力があるだろう
But what's interesting about it is that it says
しかし、興味深いのは、こう書かれていることです。
it will tell you
それはあなたに教えてくれるでしょう
people who use power will tell you
権力を行使する人々はあなたに言うだろう
I use this power because
私がこの力を使うのは、
I have a legal process
法的手続きを行っています
so it is
それはそうです
Planning to be publicly desirable
公的に望ましいとされる計画
Which means I did it to you because
つまり、私があなたにこんなことをしたのは、
I have to look out for the interests of the majority
私は多数派の利益を考慮しなければなりません
example
例
or if I don't
あるいは私がそうしなければ
i may be other
私は他の人かもしれない
Like things like destroyed by power
力によって破壊されるようなもの
so this is a very interesting feeling
これはとても興味深い感覚です
what is authority
権威とは何ですか
authority it must imply power
権威、それは権力を意味するものでなければならない
The base of power is violence
権力の根幹は暴力だ
so you need to know
だからあなたは知る必要があります
These concepts are related
これらの概念は関連しています
then let's see
それでは見てみましょう
the front side
前側
good
良い
let's think again
もう一度考えてみましょう
That is to say, under what circumstances
つまり、どのような状況下で
what kind of situation
どのような状況ですか
We don't need Authority
私たちに権威は必要ありません
this is an interesting question
これは興味深い質問です
We just said Power is important
先ほどパワーが重要だと言いました
We can't imagine saying a government has no rights
政府には権利がないと言うことは想像できない
but you think backwards
でもあなたは逆向きに考えます
what kind of situation
どのような状況ですか
We don't need Power
私たちには力は必要ありません
You ask an economist and he'll tell you
経済学者に聞けば教えてくれる
why would he tell you
なぜ彼はあなたに言うのでしょうか
Because he said at least when I was young
少なくとも私が若い頃に彼はこう言っていたから
When I was a freshman
私が新入生のとき
Learn that individual economics, he told you
個人の経済学を学びなさい、と彼は言いました
the market is perfect
市場は完璧です
invisible hand
見えざる手
This sentence is really good
この一文は本当に良いですね
I can’t even see my hands, how can there be Power
手すら見えないのに、どうして力が生まれるのでしょう
know what i mean
わかる
economist at least
少なくとも経済学者
I studied economics at that time
私は当時経済学を勉強していました
he told me
彼は私に言った
The Greatest Economist
最も偉大な経済学者
just an invisible hand
ただの見えざる手
telling us what to do
私たちに何をすべきか教えてください
OK, what is the invisible hand?
さて、見えざる手とは何ですか？
You have no idea where Power is
パワーがどこにあるのか全く分かりません
Of course there are some market rules
もちろん市場ルールはあります
Under a certain market rule, you really can’t see it
ある市場ルールの下では本当に見えない
There are market forces
市場原理が存在する
But there are still many places in our human life
しかし、私たちの人間の生活にはまだ多くの場所があります
not only hands can see
手だけが見えるわけではない
and he wants you to see
そして彼はあなたに見てもらいたいのです
OK
OK
If you see you ignore me
あなたが私を無視しているのを見たら
I will use the next step
次のステップで使用します
know what i mean
わかる
So the human phenomenon is very complicated
人間の現象は非常に複雑です
But economists are less likely to talk about this
しかし、経済学者はこのことについて話す可能性が低い
because they want
彼らが望んでいるから
The final order of the market is when it is invisible
市場の最終的な順序は目に見えないときです
dominating everything
すべてを支配する
OK
OK
So if you use game theory to solve these problems in economics
ゲーム理論を使って経済学の問題を解決すると、
you will have a problem
問題が発生するでしょう
So what
だから何
I figured it out for a long time, if the final result is what will happen naturally
長い間考えてた、最終結果が自然に起こるなら
Why do I use the game to solve it?
なぜゲームを使って解決するのでしょうか?
know what i mean
わかる
You can of course predict an equilibrium
もちろん均衡を予測することもできます
Then this equilibrium is that everyone
この均衡は、誰もが
he only for himself
彼は自分のためだけに
pursue the best interests
最善の利益を追求する
society as a whole will achieve the greatest benefit
社会全体が最大の利益を達成する
Right
右
It seems that many economists still think this way
多くの経済学者は今でもそう考えているようだ
But for the time being, economists believe
しかし当面、経済学者らは次のように考えている。
I also admit that there is such a world
そういう世界があることも認めます
But it's not all of the world
でもそれが世界のすべてではない
if your game is really interesting
あなたのゲームが本当に面白いなら
you should imagine a situation
状況を想像したほうがいいよ
is when I'm looking for my best interest
それは私が自分の最善の利益を探しているときです
I will cause inconvenience to others
他の人に迷惑をかけてしまう
Only in this way will there be power
そうすることでのみ力が生まれる
That's why this power says you can't do this
だからこの力はあなたにはこれはできないと言っているのです
right? that's what it means
そうですか、これが意味するところです
If this matter is beneficial to everyone
この件が皆様にとって有益であれば
but it's not what you want
でもそれはあなたが望むものではありません
then i can ask you to do this
それならあなたにこれをやってもらうことができます
That is to say we are gamers
つまり我々はゲーマーなのです
will realize a very fundamental problem
非常に根本的な問題に気づくことになる
our individual rationality
私たち個人の合理性
collective irrationality
集団的不合理
know what i mean
わかる
That is to say, of course we personally can pursue
つまり、もちろん個人的に追求することもできます
your own interests
あなた自身の興味
But you have to see what the result is
しかし、結果がどうなるかは見なければなりません
Could be a disaster for the collective
集団にとって災難となる可能性がある
Of course I'm not talking about all social actions
もちろん、私はすべての社会的行為について話しているわけではありません
or society's choice must be
あるいは社会が選択する必要があります
But we cannot rule out the possibility
しかし、可能性を排除することはできません
is ubiquitous
遍在している
wait a minute we'll see
ちょっと待ってください。
Where does this possibility exist?
この可能性はどこにあるのでしょうか?
ok now let's see
さて、それでは見てみましょう
These three things we now fill it up
この 3 つを今埋めます
The first of course is to say
もちろん最初に言うのは、
From the origin of history
歴史の起源から
We will now give you a brief summary
これから簡単な概要を説明します
That is, the reason why statistics
つまり、なぜ統計があるのか​​というと、
because some people
なぜなら一部の人は
He is in the process of building the modern nation
彼は近代国家を建設中だ
Need to know where his population is
彼の人口がどこにあるのかを知る必要がある
this is not a simple question
これは単純な質問ではありません
We now think that this problem is too simple
私たちは今、この問題は単純すぎると考えています
Let's do a national census
国勢調査をしましょう
Just think about how it was possible 400 years ago
400年前にどうやってそれが可能だったのか考えてみてください
it's very very difficult
とてもとても難しいです
So who can figure it out first
それで誰が最初にそれを理解できるか
A better way to estimate
より良い見積もり方法
OK, how many people do I rule?
OK、私は何人を統治できるでしょうか？
then i can count
そうすれば数えられるよ
How many adults can serve in the military?
大人は何人まで兵役に就くことができますか?
When I calculate more accurately
もっと正確に計算してみると
If the opponent is not sure, I may win him.
相手が自信を持っていない場合は、私が勝つかもしれません。
So just started his origin
それで彼の起源が始まったばかりです
Indeed, because some people
確かに、人によっては
In the process of forming modernity
近代性が形成される過程で
he needs to get to know people
彼は人々と知り合う必要がある
OK that's the fundamental reason
はい、それが根本的な理由です
I'm going to find out who I rule over
私が誰を支配しているのかを見つけ出すつもりです
second what do i do
2番目に何をしますか
usually for war
通常は戦争のため
Don't forget it's the book
それが本であることを忘れないでください
the one just mentioned
今言ったもの
The book The Nature and Political Observations
The Nature and Political Observations那本書
it 1663
それ 1663
what is the significance of 1663
1663年にはどんな意味があるのか
1663 you are going to push forward
1663 君は前に突き進むつもりだ
In 1648, a very important concept came out
1648年に非常に重要な概念が出てきました
modern state
現代国家
Do you understand?
わかりますか？
We now use the watershed of the modern state
私たちは今、現代国家の分水嶺を利用しています
Probably Vesuvalia 1648
おそらくヴェスヴァリア 1648
How to say in Chinese
中国語で何と言いますか
kyphalia
キファ​​リア
that's it
それでおしまい
Cifalia system
シファリアシステム
is what we see now
それが今私たちが見ているものです
Actually Europe
実はヨーロッパ
The embryonic form of that time
その時の胎動
probably
おそらく
It is Vesuvalia
ヴェスヴァリアです
that meeting
その会議
it's set out to say
それは言うように設定されています
we are doing international politics now
私たちは今国際政治を行っています
do international relations
国際関係をする
you need to know
あなたは知る必要があります
We still follow this system
私たちは今でもこのシステムに従っています
As far as Modern State
近代国家に至るまで
So it's probably around the same time
なので、おそらく同じ頃だと思います
so it's realistic
だからそれは現実的です
That is to say, when the modern state is already in the process of forming
つまり、すでに近代国家が形成されつつあるとき、
At this time, there will be conflicts between countries
この時、国家間で紛争が起こるだろう
Then your conflict could lead to war
そうすればあなたの対立は戦争につながるかもしれません
Then you start a war who will win
それから戦争を始めると誰が勝つか
because he is modern
彼は現代人だから
So he must have used the so-called scientific method
したがって、彼はいわゆる科学的手法を使用したに違いありません
If I can use the minimum cost
最低限のコストで使えれば
Estimate how many people I can rule
私が統治できる人数を見積もってください
how much food can i smoke
どれくらいの量の食べ物を吸ってもいいですか
OK how many adult males can I send to the battlefield
OK、何人の成人男性を戦場に送ればいいですか
Then he won't report to the police
だったら警察には通報しないだろうね
he's more likely to win
彼は勝つ可能性が高い
Of course I know that human beings have always had this need
もちろん、人類が常にこのようなニーズを持っていることは知っています
But when Europe has become a system of modern states
しかし、ヨーロッパが近代国家システムになったとき、
We need to know that at this time he has a very intense competitive pressure
私たちは現時点で彼が非常に激しい競争プレッシャーを抱えていることを知っておく必要があります
The strange thing is
奇妙なのは、
Of course science has a chance
もちろん科学にはチャンスがある
Because modernity inherently has a characteristic
近代性には本質的に特徴があるから
called scientific
科学的と呼ばれる
This is the system
これがシステムです
So from the perspective of historical development
したがって、歴史的発展の観点から見ると、
We know that the statistics come out
統計が出ているのは知っていますが、
related to acts of war
戦争行為に関連したもの
So he must have something to do with politics
ということは、彼は政治と何らかの関係があるに違いない
ok then let's talk
わかりました、それでは話しましょう
From the essence of these three theories
この３つの理論の本質から
Does it have some correlation
何か相関関係があるのでしょうか
Then I think today this
それから今日はこう思います
this is what i really want to talk about
これが私が本当に話したいことです
Tongji
同済
Games and Politics
ゲームと政治
what is its relevance
その関連性は何ですか
OK
OK
I think you can start thinking about this now
今から考え始めてもいいと思います
Why do we three things tie it together
なぜ 3 つのことが結びつくのか
no way to take it apart
分解する方法はありません
so we can now
だから今できる
Take these three things a little
この3つを少しずつ取り入れていきましょう
rephrase
rephrase一下
we will say
私たちは言います
because there are three dots
点が3つあるので
right
右
statistics game politics
統計ゲーム 政治
Then we just said
それから私たちはこう言いました
If you go through game theory
ゲーム理論を理解してみると
when your forecast is invisible
予測が見えないとき
then why do we need games
ではなぜゲームが必要なのか
know what i mean
わかる
game theory
ゲーム理論
Began to become influential to economists
経済学者に影響力を持ち始める
It's because people don't believe that time
人々があの時を信じていないからだ
out of sight
見えない所に
Right
右
This should come naturally
これは自然に起こるはずです
He told you that I let you see every day
彼はあなたに毎日会わせていると言いました
so the country becomes important
だから国が重要になる
So game theory he actually told us that
ゲーム理論 彼は実際に私たちにこう言いました
There are some things that constantly need someone to do it
常に誰かにやってもらう必要があることがいくつかある
Can't really believe in the invisible
目に見えないものは本当に信じられない
so we now know
それで私たちは今知っています
That is to say, politics has something to do with the game.
つまり、ゲームには政治が関係しているということだ。
let me ask you another question
別の質問をさせてください
What is political science? Have you ever thought about it?
政治学とは何ですか? 考えたことはありますか?
I forgot to ask you this question
この質問をするのを忘れていました
yeah so i'm going to ask you now
はい、それでは今から聞いてみます
I'm kidding everyone
みんな冗談だよ
I remember my freshman year
1年生の頃を思い出します
When I was a sophomore, I took a class
2年生の時に授業を受けました
The teacher will ask you a question
先生があなたに質問します
What do you think is the difference between politics and economics?
政治と経済の違いは何だと思いますか?
You should know economics
経済学を知るべきだ
what is economics
経済学とは何ですか
is there another point
他にポイントはありますか
Which one do you think is more important
どちらがより重要だと思いますか?
The way resources were just allocated
リソースが割り当てられたばかりの方法
any left
少し残っている
all good
大丈夫です
Do you have any other comments?
他に何かコメントはありますか？
Ok, Ok
はいはい
Well, this definition is very good
まあ、この定義は非常に良いです
Let's come back to this definition later
この定義には後で戻りましょう
just over there
ちょうどそこにある
good
良い
Then the answer I heard at that time
あの時聞いた答えは
scare me
私を怖がらせます
what is economics
経済学とは何ですか
economics first
まずは経済学
Economics is easier to understand
経済学は理解しやすい
economics is in
経済学は入っている
With limited resources
限られたリソースの中で
For your resources
あなたのリソースのために
for the best reason, right?
一番の理由ですよね？
because it must have a condition
条件があるはずだから
i.e. your resources
つまり、あなたのリソース
not infinite expansion
無限の拡大ではない
Just under this given condition
まさにこの与えられた条件下で
The reason you do the best with resources
リソースを最大限に活用する理由
right?
右？
probably acceptable
おそらく許容できる
Then the politics are exactly the same
それなら政治も全く同じだ
really
本当
True learning is to make the best use of limited resources
本当の学びとは、限られたリソースを最大限に活用することです
Aren't these two disciplines the same?
この 2 つの分野は同じではありませんか?
Zhenxue plus two words
Zhenxue と 2 つの単語
Make the best use of the limited resources of others
他人の限られたリソースを最大限に活用する
This is the fundamental difference between the two disciplines
これが 2 つの分野の根本的な違いです
Why does the government tax
なぜ政府は税金を払うのか
Didn't we start off by saying it's taxpayer money?
国民の税金だと言って始めたじゃないですか。
yes
はい
so he needs to rationalize
だから彼は合理化する必要がある
He said that if there is no tax collection, there will be problems in society.
徴税がなければ社会に問題が生じるだろうと彼は言った。
so you just have to pay him taxes
だからあなたは彼に税金を払えばいいだけです
do you really not pay taxes
本当に税金を払っていないのですか
waiting behind waiting for you
後ろで待ってあなたを待っています
So political phenomena must be compulsive
したがって、政治現象は強制的でなければなりません
So why would he follow some political science
ではなぜ彼は政治学を学んだのでしょうか
such as ethics
倫理などの
would even say that a large part of political philosophy is discussing this issue
政治哲学の大部分がこの問題を議論しているとさえ言うだろう
How the state can justify its coercion against you
国家はあなたに対する強制をどのように正当化できるか
ok, this is a very big difference between political science and economics
OK、これは政治学と経済学の大きな違いです
But in essence, it is the best use of resources
しかし本質的には、それがリソースの最大限の活用です
just one is its own resource
1 つだけが独自のリソースです
one is someone else's resource
1 つは他の人のリソースです
just kidding
冗談だ
alright
大丈夫
we now return to political science
ここで政治学の話に戻ります
Political science, in fact, we just talked about it like this
政治学、実際、私たちはちょうどこのように話し合ったばかりです
game theory
ゲーム理論
if it's going to be useful
それが役に立つなら
In fact, it should be more useful for political science
実際、政治学にはもっと役立つはずです
Why
なぜ
Because its core concept is strategy
その核となる概念は戦略であるため、
what is strategy
戦略とは何ですか
strategy means that it is at your hand
戦略とは、それがあなたの手の中にあることを意味します
For example, in the case of three sides
例えば3辺の場合
which one do you think is more important
どちらがより重要だと思いますか
Right
右
Then you said that the public funds should be included in the basic public funds
それから、基礎的公的資金の中に公的資金を入れるべきだとおっしゃいました。
It's better to raise it to 30,000 yuan
3万円に上げた方が良いですよ
or to solve other problems first
または、最初に他の問題を解決する
something like this
このようなもの
That is to say, you have to choose a strategy
つまり、戦略を選択する必要があります
And each strategy choice
そしてそれぞれの戦略の選択
may have to be considered
考慮する必要があるかもしれない
Will the other party
相手は
For example, the basic salary is increased to 30,000 yuan.
例えば、基本給は3万元に引き上げられる。
Will there be some adverse effects
何らかの悪影響はあるのでしょうか
issues such as
などの問題
OK
OK
this is a link
これはリンクです
then ask
その後尋ねます
What is the relationship between politics and statistics?
政治と統計にはどのような関係があるのでしょうか?
yes
はい
Just one relatively capable
比較的有能な1人だけ
Of course he hopes that his current decision is based on an objective basis
もちろん、彼は現在の意思決定が客観的な根拠に基づいていることを望んでいます
right base above
正確的基礎上面
So one thing we need to know is that
そこで、私たちが知っておく必要があることが 1 つあります。
sorry
ごめん
When the concept of statistics began to be accepted by everyone
統計という概念が誰もに受け入れられ始めた頃
The first will apply statistics
最初は統計を適用します
In fact, it is a government agency
実は政府機関です
OK is a government agency
OK は政府機関です
Because he feels his rule must be based on a proper understanding of the society I control
なぜなら、彼は自分の統治が私が管理する社会の適切な理解に基づいていなければならないと感じているからです。
let's talk backwards
逆に話しましょう
If there are some governments when he doesn't actually do that
彼が実際にはそうしない政府がいくつかあるとしたら
In fact, his life span will be shorter
実際寿命は短くなるだろう
because you're not building on the right foundation
適切な基盤の上に構築していないからです
OK so he might be wrong
OK、だから彼は間違っているかもしれない
OK so we know
OK、わかっています
Then there is another line that I want to talk about today.
それから、今日話したいことはもう一つあります。
So what is the relationship between game theory and statistics?
では、ゲーム理論と統計学の関係は何でしょうか?
right
右
We have drawn two lines
2本の線を引いてみました
one more line
もう一行
What do you think is the relationship?
どういう関係だと思いますか？
Let's look at it from the concept of paying money
お金を払うという概念から見てみましょう
we would feel like saying
私たちは言いたくなるでしょう
The so-called Game Theory, it predicts what you will do
いわゆるゲーム理論、それはあなたが何をするかを予測します
Does statistics try to predict the condition of the mother with the least cost?
統計は、最小限のコストで母親の状態を予測しようとしているのでしょうか?
So what's the relationship between these two?
それで、この二人の関係は何でしょうか？
would you like to talk more
もっと話したいですか
I'd love to hear your answer let me have a sip of water
ぜひ答えを聞きたいです、水を一口飲ませてください
The mayor was in the defense plane, did he ever execute
市長は防衛機に乗っていたが、処刑したことはあるのか
Game isn't it?
ゲームですよね？
Mayor, you and Luo Fa were locked up during the entire operation
市長、あなたとルオ・ファは作戦中ずっと監禁されていました
so what do you do
それであなたは何をしますか
Fu Yu Lun you agree
フー・ユー・ルン、あなたは同意します
I ask Fu Yulun in front of you if you agree
あなたの目の前でフー・ユルンに同意するか尋ねます
alright
大丈夫
Well, I think it's all right
まあ、大丈夫だと思います
I think someone who has an opinion
意見がある人だと思う
Actually, I think you've got the answer to your question.
実際、あなたの質問に対する答えは得られたと思います。
we are in this world
私たちはこの世界にいます
The most important thing about modernity is that I'm anxious
現代について最も重要なことは、私が不安であるということです
so i must win
だから私は勝たなければなりません
do you understand what i mean
私の言っている意味が分かりますか
Previously people may not have this state
以前は人々はこの状態にならなかったかもしれません
but modern is
しかし現代は
it will tell you one thing
それはあなたに一つのことを教えてくれるでしょう
This is a competitive society
これは競争社会です
you want to survive
あなたは生き残れるようになりたいのです
you are about to win
あなたはもうすぐ勝ちます
something you know to win
勝つために知っていること
OK, the worst I have ever seen is the students in Singapore
OK、私がこれまで見た中で最悪なのはシンガポールの学生です
He is worse than Taiwanese students
彼は台湾の学生よりも劣っている
Because they have been divided into classes since childhood
子供の頃からクラス分けされているので、
For EM1, EM2, EM3
EM1、EM2、EM3用
that's not mysterious at all
それはまったく神秘的ではありません
What are EM1, EM2, EM3
EM1、EM2、EM3とは何ですか
E is for English
Eは英語です
M is for Mathematics
Mは数学です
So you get a grade from a young age
だから若い頃から成績が上がるんだよ
but your ranking in all singapore
でもシンガポール全体でのあなたのランキングは
know what i mean
わかる
I don't know if that's the case now
今もそうなのかは分かりませんが
But they are very competitive
しかし、彼らは非常に競争力がある
His EM3 ​​person
彼のEM3の人
He already told you from primary school
彼は小学校の時からすでに言っていた
Said you are the person from EM3
あなたはEM3の人だと言いました
So his system is very
彼のシステムは非常に優れています
It's actually pretty scary
実はかなり怖いんです
But he is based on statistics
しかし彼は統計に基づいています
but tell you
でも言ってください
You are among the children in Singapore who are all grade 1
あなたもシンガポールの小学 1 年生の子供たちの一人です
where do you rank
あなたは何位にランクされますか
that pressure is very high
そのプレッシャーは非常に高いです
I want to say that I will definitely be there
必ず行きますって言いたい
will win you soon
すぐにあなたに勝ちます
This to his immigrant in a sea of ​​people
これは人の海の中の彼の移民へ
what i'm trying to say is
私が言いたいのは、
There is a system that does it like this
こういうことをするシステムがあります
But even if you don't have such a system
しかし、たとえそのようなシステムがなかったとしても、
The characteristic of modern society is, of course, that
現代社会の特徴は言うまでもなく、
except in a competitive environment
競争環境以外では
in a very intense society
非常に厳しい社会の中で
Everything is ranking
すべてはランキングです
And I'm just talking about one thing
そして、私はただ一つのことについて話しているだけです
That is to say, the concept of time
つまり時間の概念
part of modernity
現代性の一部
People in the past were not so precise
昔の人はそこまで正確ではなかった
Tell me what time, minutes and seconds
何時、何分、何秒かを教えてください
you see i've been looking behind
わかるでしょう、私は後ろを見てきました
what time is it
今何時ですか
because i have to do the next thing
次のことをしなければならないから
so when your time is being
だからあなたの時間があるときに
when cut into very precise units
非常に正確な単位に切断する場合
All your stuff will come from here
すべてのものはここから来ます
measure your price
自分の価格を測る
not value but price
価値ではなく価格
So of course modernity has a characteristic
もちろん、近代性には特徴があります
which means you'll be in a competitive situation
つまり、競争的な状況に陥ることになります
That's why I say that in fact statistics started
だからこそ私は、実際に統計が始まったと言うのです。
It is in the process of modern state competition
近代国家競争の過程にある
There are some people who want to use the lowest cost
できるだけ安く使いたい人もいる
to get the best estimate
最良の見積もりを得るには
aim is to win
目的は勝つことです
what is winning
何が勝っているのか
To win is to beat the opponent
勝つとは相手を倒すこと
so i know say
だから私は言うことを知っています
There is a link like this
こんなリンクがあります
But what is the relationship between statistics and games?
しかし、統計とゲームの間にはどのような関係があるのでしょうか?
Has anyone thought about this
誰かこれについて考えた人はいますか
I wish you didn't say that last sentence
最後の一言は言わなければよかったのに
no i feel close
いや、近くに感じます
very close
とても近い
never mind
どうでも
what is your major
ご専攻は
your business department
あなたのビジネス部門
I think it makes sense
それは理にかなっていると思います
that is
あれは
Anyway, for most people
とにかく、ほとんどの人にとって
You can't understand the paper of the game or the paper of statistics
ゲームの論文も統計の論文も理解できない
ok
Ok
joke
ジョーク
In fact, what you said is probably substantive.
実際、あなたの言ったことはおそらく本質的です。
But it has one fundamental difference
しかし、根本的な違いが 1 つあります
That is to say, through game theory,
つまり、ゲーム理論を通して、
The predictions you are making are decisive
あなたが立てている予測は決定的です
deterministic
決定的な
right
右
it will tell you which strategy is best
どの戦略が最適かを教えてくれる
which strategy is best
どの戦略が最適ですか
Right
右
For example, I now have three
たとえば、今私は3つ持っています
Then after my estimation
それから私の見積もりの​​後
I think the first time might be best
初回が一番いいかも知れません
it tells you
それはあなたに伝えます
first time best
初めてのベスト
that's it
それでおしまい
when you do statistics
統計を行うとき
it won't tell you advice
それはアドバイスにはなりません
it will tell you
それはあなたに教えてくれるでしょう
Each strategy has its different amount of variation
各戦略には異なる量のバリエーションがあります
So it has a fundamental difference
つまり根本的な違いがあるのです
one tells you what to do
1つはあなたに何をすべきかを教えます
and another one tells you
そして別の人があなたに言います
How to Minimize Your Variation
変動を最小限に抑える方法
or minimize your residuals
または残差を最小限に抑える
right
右
what do we call
私たちは何と呼びますか
A good statistical model
優れた統計モデル
It can try to make your arrow term
矢印の項を作成しようとする可能性があります
The sum of the squares of is the lowest
の二乗和が最小になります
This is called the method of least squares
これを最小二乗法といいます
but it won't tell you
でもそれは教えてくれない
what are you supposed to do
何をすればいいですか
But the game it will tell you
でもそれが教えてくれるゲーム
which one is the thing you should do
あなたがすべきことはどれですか
then i think you got the point
それなら、あなたは要点を理解していると思います
That is to say, these two things
つまり、この２つ
It's two sides of the same coin
それは同じコインの裏表です
when i'm making a decision
私が決断を下すとき
I know when I should
いつすべきかはわかっています
But who can guarantee you
でも誰があなたを保証できるの
Said it must be the best strategy
それが最善の戦略に違いないと言いました
So it must have error
したがってエラーがあるはずです
So people who do game theory
ゲーム理論をやっている人たちは
its one of the most troublesome things
それは最も厄介なことの一つです
That is to say, in fact you look through the mathematical model
つまり、実際には数学モデルを調べます。
deduced results
推定結果
is mathematically true
数学的には正しいです
but actually don't know
しかし実際には分かりません
But you said that in fact you really don't know?
でも実際のところは分からないって言ってたよね？
nor
または
It will tell you the difference in probability
確率の違いがわかります
It will say, for example, you choose the first strategy now
たとえば、今最初の戦略を選択したと表示されます。
that should be true
それは本当のはずです
But is it really guaranteed?
しかし、それは本当に保証されているのでしょうか？
You need classmates and scholars to help you
あなたを助けてくれるクラスメートや学者が必要です
know what i mean
わかる
That is to say, it plays a different role
つまり役割が違うのです
one tells you what to do
1つはあなたに何をすべきかを教えます
The other one tells you how high the risk of doing this is
もう 1 つは、これを行うリスクがいかに高いかを示しています。
But I don't think you can take it apart
でも分解できないと思うよ
so it becomes
そうなります
When we look at these two disciplines
この2つの分野を見てみると、
Wait a minute I'm introducing the definition in the middle
ちょっと待ってください、途中で定義を紹介します
that something
その何か
When we look at these two disciplines
この2つの分野を見てみると、
very funny
非常に面白い
It's just that their tendencies are different
ただ傾向が違うだけです
But the problems they face are actually very similar
しかし、彼らが直面している問題は実際には非常に似ています
that is, when we are making a decision
つまり、決断を下すとき
what decision is better
どのような決断が良いのか
It's a matter of game
それはゲームの問題だ
Another one is to say
もう一つはこう言うことです
when we are sampling
サンプリングをしているとき
which sampling method
どのサンプリング方法か
Which statistical model
どの統計モデル
can minimize the level of our error items
エラー項目のレベルを最小限に抑えることができます
it equals the way because otherwise the government would offset it
そうしないと政府が相殺してしまうため、それは同じ道である
OK so it's actually facing the same kind of thing
OK、それは実際に同じ種類のものに直面しているということです
Then can we find a link between them?
それでは、それらの間のつながりを見つけることができるでしょうか？
Let's take a look at the equation in the middle
真ん中の方程式を見てみましょう
don't think it's scary
怖いとは思わないでください
It means that this is a Basein thing
つまり、これはバセインのものだということです
B-A-Y-E-S-I-M Basein Stuff
B-A-Y-E-S-I-M ベースインのもの
it's called... let's just call it the back
それは...バックと呼ぶことにしましょう
Its concept is like this
そのコンセプトはこんな感じ
That is to say, back statistics should be called back rules
つまり、バック統計はバックルールと呼ぶ必要があります。
it has a belief
それは信念を持っています
It's Thomas Base who told us one thing
トーマス・ベースが私たちに一つ教えてくれました
Any of our decisions can be based on a Prior
当社の決定はいずれも事前の情報に基づいて行われることがあります。
a bright faith above
上にある明るい信仰
like i think you're good
私があなたが良いと思うように
But are you really good? I want to observe you
でも本当に上手いの?観察したい
Then I can update based on my observation of you
そうすれば、あなたの観察に基づいて更新できます
renew my beliefs
自分の信念を新たにする
That is to say, a person can have his own beliefs about anything
つまり、人は何についても自分の信念を持つことができるということです
doesn't matter
無所謂
But I can see through my constant observation of you
でも、あなたをいつも観察しているとわかるよ
and make my beliefs closer to the truth
そして私の信念を真実に近づけます
This is not the same as the concept of classical statistics
これは古典的な統計の概念と同じではありません
OK means that I can make my prior belief through my observation
OK は、観察を通じて以前の信念を証明できることを意味します
slowly approaching the real situation
徐々に実態に近づいていく
So it must have conditional probability
したがって、条件付き確率が必要です
Conditional probability means that
条件付き確率とは、
For example, we see here
たとえば、ここで見ます
That prdT means
prdT が意味するのは、
Given T then the probability that D is true
T が与えられると、D が真である確率
OK let me talk again
OK、もう一度話しましょう
Just the one over here define
ここで定義されているものだけ
This pr means
このprの意味は、
prdT means
prdT とは
You have to look at the probability of T existence first
まず T が存在する確率を調べなければなりません
Then look at the probability that T exists
次に、T が存在する確率を見てください。
part of D
Dの一部
How high is the proportion of
の割合はどのくらい高いのか
OK so you have to give a condition first
OK、最初に条件を与える必要があります
Then look at the condition where the condition exists
次に、条件が存在する条件を見てください。
Below is the prior belief you are interested in
以下はあなたが興味がある以前の信念です
what are the chances it's true
それが本当である可能性はどのくらいですか
and what is this on the right
そして右側のこれは何ですか
That's data when you don't have any theory
それは理論がないときのデータです
So we can define a thing
したがって、物事を定義できます
That is to say, you can see the gap between the two
つまり、両者の間にギャップが見られるということです。
One is that you don't have any theory
一つは理論がないということ
Another one is that you have a theory
もう一つは、あなたには理論があるということです
Then you have to look at the difference between the two
次に、この 2 つの違いを確認する必要があります
Of course we know that the greater the gap between the two
もちろん、両者の差が大きくなればなるほど、
I give a simple example
簡単な例を挙げます
For example, when I was a child, I really liked watching detective decimals.
たとえば、私は子供の頃、『十数探偵』を見るのが大好きでした。
Then I think the most interesting one is of course that Sherlock Holmes
そして、最も興味深いのは、もちろんシャーロック・ホームズだと思います。
I heard he's going to act recently, right?
最近演技するって聞いたんだけど？
do you want
欲しいですか
to the UK
イギリスへ
then i think they
それなら彼らだと思います
Really
本当
OK
OK
i heard there was this movie
こんな映画があると聞いた
So what I'm trying to say is that
それで、私が言いたいのは、
I think the most interesting thing about him is telling us what reasoning is
彼の最も興味深い点は、推論とは何かを私たちに教えてくれることだと思います。
Reasoning is actually a very interesting process
推論は実際には非常に興味深いプロセスです
He tells you that you can see the same things as normal people
普通の人と同じものを見ることができると彼は言います
For example, the police can see this thing
たとえば、警察はこれを見ることができます
Detectives can also see this thing
探偵もこれを見ることができます
Then why are their conclusions different?
では、なぜ彼らの結論は異なるのでしょうか？
That's the interesting question, isn't it?
それは興味深い質問ですね。
That is to say, the data you see is the same
つまり、表示されるデータは同じです
OK
OK
But what about this
しかし、これはどうでしょうか
When a detective doesn't have any theories
探偵に理論がないとき
He wants to say that's all
彼はそれだけだと言いたいのです
But Holmes, he can take a closer look
でもホームズ、彼ならもっと詳しく見ることができるよ
Looking around, he said OK
周りを見回して、彼はOKと言った
This is what a left-handed person does
左利きの人はこうするんだよ
why can he do this
なぜ彼はこんなことができるのか
this is an interesting question
これは興味深い質問です
why it can be deduced
なぜそれが推測できるのか
Said the case was a left-handed
この事件は左利きだったと言った
Because you have to look carefully at the evidence at the scene
現場の証拠を注意深く見なければならないからです
because it can see something that others also see
他の人にも見えるものを見ることができるからです
But others don't know why
しかし他の人はその理由を知りません
that is a very simple truth
それはとても単純な真実です
That is, if you see a pipe
つまり、パイプが見えたら
It is, for example, left over from the chest hand
たとえば、胸の手の残りです
what do you want to see
あなたは何が見たいですか
You want to see which side it burns
どちら側が燃えるか見てみたい
know what i mean
わかる
So you can immediately generate a chain of inferences
そのため、一連の推論を即座に生成できます。
If we are right-handed
私たちが右利きなら
Which hand do I hold the pipe with?
どちらの手でパイプを持ちますか？
i don't smoke now
私は今はタバコを吸いません
So this example is not good
したがって、この例は良くありません
So you have to know that in the 19th century
ですから、19世紀にはそれを知っておく必要があります
everyone smokes pipes
みんなパイプを吸う
so you just have to watch which side it burns
だからどちら側が燃えるのかを見ていればいいんだ
You can make a series of inferences saying
次のような一連の推論を行うことができます
This is a pipe it usually uses
普段使っているパイプです
it must be left handed
それは左利きでなければなりません
So this thing is
それで、これは
you see the same thing
あなたも同じものを見ます
But you because you have a theory
でもあなたには理論があるから
say it might be left handed
それは左利きかもしれないと言う
Then you see this phenomenon
するとこの現象が見られます
later you will carry people
後で人を運ぶことになります
you will carry people's guesses
あなたは人々の推測を運ぶでしょう
OK, that so-called powerful detective
OK、いわゆる強力な探偵です
He's looking for that tiny piece of evidence
彼はその小さな証拠を探している
Because he can find a lot of
彼は現場から多くのことを見つけることができるから
Things that most people think are unimportant
ほとんどの人が重要ではないと考えていること
Then he will slowly make his theory true
そうすれば彼はゆっくりと自分の理論を真実にするだろう
Say it's not just for lefties
左利きだけのものではないと言う
and he may be poor
そして彼は貧しいかもしれない
or something like this
またはこのようなもの
and he's funny
そして彼は面白いです
I couldn't understand when I was a child
子供の頃は理解できなかった
Now fully understand what he's talking about
現在完全了解他在講
He said that after you rule out the impossible possibility
彼は、不可能な可能性を排除した後だと言いました
the rest is possible
残りは可能です
This is what Base tells you
これがBaseがあなたに伝えることです
because when you see a D
なぜなら、Dを見ると
When a Data
データが
You have to know that he sometimes comes from T
彼は時々 T から来ることを知っておく必要があります
Right? Your Theory
そうですか？あなたの理論
But sometimes it comes from not T
しかし、時にはそれはTではないことから来ます
So you just find the
それであなたはただ見つけます
The chances that he might spawn from something other than T are very low
彼が T 以外のものからスポーンする可能性は非常に低いです
Then you believe he is from T
それなら彼は T 出身だと思います
small T
小T
OK that's a very simple reasoning logic
これは非常に単純な推論ロジックです
But I think it's very helpful
でもとても役に立つと思います
That's why I will say next
だから次に言います
that T and D
そのTとD
Miss T and D
TさんとDさん
It is probably a Theory and a Data we talked about
それはおそらく私たちが話した理論とデータです
Your physics department is very good
あなたの物理学科はとても優秀です
what is experiment
実験とは何ですか
right
右
It is on the computer as long as it is behind the work
仕事の背後にある限り、それはコンピュータ上にあります
then we can see its secret
そうすればその秘密がわかります
right
右
just see all the information
すべての情報を見てください
So you can't put it on me
だからあなたはそれを私に押し付けることはできません
So it can't be put into the experiment
だから実験には入れられない
right
右
There is a very important principle in your experiment
あなたの実験には非常に重要な原則があります
That means you need treatment
つまり治療が必要です
then you must know one thing
それなら一つ知っておくべきことがある
You give it treatment and it will generate data
処理するとデータが生成されます
You did not give it treatment it will not generate data
処理を行っていないため、データは生成されません
So PRD is equal to you
つまり PRD はあなたと同等です
do you understand what i mean
私の言っている意味が分かりますか
That is to say, the PRD behind this formula
つまり、この式の背後にある PRD
it won't generate
それは生産しません
because you didn't give it treatment
あなたが治療しなかったから
so the previous one
それで前のは
The conditional probability is the PRDT
条件付き確率は PRDT です
it is E
それはEです
because you give it treatment it will produce
あなたがそれを治療するからそれは生まれるでしょう
So you are comparing the gap between the two
つまり、2つの間のギャップを比較しているのです
when it is equal to E
Eに等しいとき
you just believe it's true
あなたはそれが真実だと信じているだけです
The big t is called truth
大きなTは真実と呼ばれます
It can also be called theory
理論とも言えます
good
良い
So this probably means
つまり、これはおそらく意味します
We're connecting games with statistics
ゲームと統計を結びつけています
In fact, you can use the concept of a Base
実際、Base の概念を使用できます。
connect it
接続してください
on the one hand
一方では
What the game tells you is
ゲームが教えてくれるのは、
sorry
ごめん
What we're doing is a prediction
私たちがやっていることは予測です
For example, an expectation
たとえば、期待
It is better for you to adopt this strategy at this time
現時点ではこの戦略を採用する方が良いでしょう
But there must be risks
でもリスクもあるはずだ
where does this risk come from
このリスクはどこから来るのか
Depends on your previous game
以前のゲームによって異なります
Is your inference reasonable?
あなたの推論は合理的ですか?
OK so of course we want to say
OK、もちろん言いたいのは
The prediction we make is
私たちが行う予測は
There are some, say, theories
たとえば、いくつかの理論があります
tell you that you should do this
あなたはこれをすべきだと言います
do this for you
あなたのためにこれをしてください
risk is relatively low
リスクは比較的低い
What is lower risk
リスクが低いとは
that is if you do
それはあなたがそうする場合です
no objection or anything like that
異論とかそういうものはありません
So it's basically two sides of the same coin.
したがって、基本的には同じコインの表裏の関係にあります。
Then this is the so-called basic link
これがいわゆる基本リンクです
Then let's see who this person is
それでは、この人が誰なのか見てみましょう
who is base
ベースは誰ですか
You put the photo like this on purpose
わざとこんな写真載せてるのね
We want because our most important job today
今日の私たちの最も重要な仕事のため、私たちは望んでいます
It's ancient, right?
それは古いですよね？
tell you a long time ago
ずっと前に言ってください
who is this
これは誰ですか
Is there anyone studying mathematics here?
ここで数学を勉強している人はいますか?
I just asked sorry
ごめんなさいと聞いただけです
Did you study math?
数学を勉強しましたか？
Then I deliberately put this photo
じゃあわざわざこの写真を載せてみた
Who is that
あれは誰
Then let me tell you a very interesting thing
それから、とても興味深いことを教えてください
This person can't take root in today's society
この人は今の社会に根付かない
Because his preparation theorem has not been published
彼の準備定理は公開されていないため、
his preparation theorem
他的備事定理
As far as the logic of the set of inferences we just talked about
先ほど話した一連の推論のロジックに関して言えば、
after he died
彼が死んだ後
After he died, his friends helped him gather
彼が亡くなった後、友人たちが彼が集まるのを手伝ってくれた
and then tell everyone
それからみんなに言います
In fact, apart from the fact that he is actually doing those things,
実際、彼が実際にそれらのことを行っているという事実は別として、
Then this is a very interesting theorem
それから、これは非常に興味深い定理です
So he can't root now
だから彼は今root化できない
The question is what did he do?
問題は彼が何をしたのかということだ。
What exactly are his other books?
彼の他の本は一体何ですか？
have you ever thought about this
これについて考えたことがありますか
Okay, let me reveal to you
さて、明かしましょう
Most of his writings are on theology
彼の著作のほとんどは神学に関するものです
Many people find it strange
多くの人がそれを奇妙に思う
because the pastor of the presbyterian church
なぜなら長老教会の牧師が
Pastor of the Presbyterian Church in England
英国長老派教会の牧師
And he's probably older than Grant
そして彼はおそらくグラントよりも年上です
a little younger
もう少し若い
Probably an English Presbyterian priest in the early 18th century
おそらく18世紀初頭のイギリスの長老派の司祭
it's fun to let him talk
彼に話させるのは楽しいよ
Because why there are Presbyterian churches in the UK
なぜなら、なぜイギリスに長老派教会があるのか​​というと、
Because of course it has something to do with the Civil War in England.
それはもちろんイギリス南北戦争と関係があるからです。
You can't finish the story of the English Civil War.
英国南北戦争の物語を終わらせることはできません。
let's not talk today
今日は話さないようにしましょう
i mean
つまり
he is a pastor of a church
彼は教会の牧師です
Presbyterian pastor
長老派の牧師
so his real job is preaching
だから彼の本当の仕事は説教することだ
Then why did he come up with the must be theorem?
ではなぜ彼はmust be定理を思いついたのでしょうか？
Have you ever thought about this
これについて考えたことはありますか
And I heard you tell me a very interesting thing
そして、とても興味深いことを言ったのを聞きました
that is to say his name has been around for a long time
つまり彼の名前は昔から存在している
people don't know
人々は知りません
Live to the last ten years
過去10年まで生きる
If you are going to take a statistics class now
これから統計学の授業を受講する場合
You need to see if he is teaching back statistics
彼が統計を教えているかどうか確認する必要がある
Back-style back is his dead back
バックスタイルの背中は彼の死んだ背中です
Then we do the game a little earlier
それから少し早くゲームをします
But after 1980, there was a game called back game
でも1980年以降は裏ゲームと呼ばれるゲームがあった
What is a back game?
バックゲームとは何ですか？
mean to say
言う意味
You can see your opponent's actions later
相手の行動を後から確認できる
you will renew your belief in who he is
あなたは彼が誰であるかという信念を新たにするでしょう
It's natural, right?
それは当然ですよね？
For example, I see you are weird
たとえば、君は変な人だね
Just check what you say and watch what you do
自分の言うことをチェックして、自分の行動を観察してください
After seeing you for a while, I feel
しばらく会ってみるとこんな感じ
You're supposed to be one of those things that I hate.
あなたは私の嫌いな人の一人であるはずです。
He wants you to see the current information
現在の情報を見てほしいとのこと
Why is he in statistics
なぜ彼は統計界にいるのか
In the last ten years, the fire has started again
過去10年で再び火がついた
because it requires a lot of calculation
多くの計算が必要になるため
require a lot of calculations
多くの計算が必要になる
Only then can you update your beliefs
そうして初めて自分の信念を更新できる
Then why does a vision think of this thing?
では、ビジョンはなぜこのようなことを考えるのでしょうか？
Because that reason is very simple
その理由は非常に単純なので、
you know what to say to him
あなたは彼に何を言えばいいか知っていますか
God is invisible, right?
神は目に見えないですよね？
God is of course invisible
神はもちろん目に見えない
But what?
でも何？
God will let you see
神はあなたに見せてくれるでしょう
things you can see
見えるもの
this is interesting
これは面白い
That is to say, you are an invisible body
つまり、あなたは目に見えない身体です
he will let you see
彼はあなたに見せてくれるでしょう
things you can see
見えるもの
so you as a believer
だからあなたは信者として
You can see signs of God every day
あなたは毎日神のしるしを見ることができます
So your Vision means this
つまり、あなたのビジョンはこれを意味します
If you are always in this state
常にこの状態だと
you will renew your beliefs
あなたは自分の信念を新たにするでしょう
belief in faith
信仰を信じる
It's just that he mathematicalized this thing
ただ彼はこれを数学化しただけです
so
それで
Probably no one wanted to publish it at the time
おそらく当時は誰も出版しようとは思わなかったでしょう
But he did write down his theories
しかし彼は自分の理論を書き留めた
So be with him as a
だから彼と一緒にいてください
Presbyterian pastors are closely related
長老派の牧師は密接な関係にある
because you since you can't see
あなたは見えないから
then why should you trust him
ではなぜ彼を信頼する必要があるのでしょうか
That's because he let you see some
それは彼があなたにいくつか見せてくれたからです
visible things
目に見えるもの
OK good
いいよ
So this is Thomas Space
これがトーマス・スペースです
That
それか
he is he must feel very strange
彼はとても奇妙に感じているに違いない
Why after 200 years
なぜ200年後なのか
suddenly began to thicken
突然太り始めた
good
良い
Finally, let's talk about a small problem
最後に小さな問題について話しましょう
that is
あれは
how do we research
どのように研究するのか
Research
研究
Authority
権限
We say that the essence of Authority is
私たちは、権威の本質は次のようなものだと言います。
How do I make the best use of other people's resources
他人のリソースを最大限に活用するにはどうすればよいですか
right
右
Then how to study him on this matter?
それでは、この問題についてどうやって彼を研究すればよいでしょうか？
This is of course the so-called political science
もちろんこれはいわゆる政治学です
There are many, many, many self-domains
自己ドメインはたくさんあります
For example, of course some of us care
たとえば、もちろん私たちの中には気にする人もいます
process of legalization
合法化のプロセス
Some people care about legitimacy
正当性を気にする人もいる
But we are also interested in saying
しかし、私たちはこう言うことにも興味があります。
Do it as a subject of empirical research
実証研究の対象として行う
What is empirical research?
実証研究とは何ですか?
we need to understand
私たちは理解する必要があります
For example, this country
たとえばこの国
This government has a policy now
この政府には現在政策があります
Since the government is pushing this policy
政府がこの政策を推し進めているので、
it must be compulsive
それは強制的でなければなりません
So we're going to ask the fundamental question
そこで根本的な質問をしてみます
does it do this well
これはうまくいきますか
what is good and bad
何が良くて何が悪いのか
becomes something that can be measured
測定できるものになる
OK so we definitely need to know a few things
OK、それではいくつかのことを知っておく必要があります
The first is to say
一つ目は言うことです
what is the advantage of it doing so
そうすることでどんなメリットがあるのか
where is the disadvantage
どこにデメリットがあるのか
Can the benefits and disadvantages be measured?
メリットとデメリットを測定できますか?
It would be fun if it couldn't be measured
計測できなかったら楽しいだろうな
That's different
それは違います
OK
OK
Although I know that politics often differs
政治が異なることが多いことは知っていますが、
But if it's on research
でもそれが研究中なら
It's all over
すべて終わった
turns into saying it doesn't have a consistent standard
一貫した基準がないと言うことになる
So there are some topics it can actually
実際にできるトピックがいくつかあります
to understand
理解する
What is the source of the so-called authority?
いわゆる権威の源泉は何でしょうか？
How many people does it benefit
何人の人に利益がもたらされるのか
OK of course we know no
もちろん、ノーはわかります
a policy
ポリシー
It should be said that the policies that most governments are promoting
ほとんどの政府が推進している政策は、
more or less limited dissatisfaction
多かれ少なかれ限定的な不満
Limited will be satisfied
限られたものなら満足できる
Then we have to measure
それから測定する必要があります
How many satisfied people are there?
満足している人は何人いますか？
How many people are dissatisfied
どれだけの人が不満を持っているのか
So this probably means
つまり、これはおそらく意味します
How do we study authority
権威をどうやって研究するか
Let me tell you this example
この例をお話ししましょう
Then this is a very, very famous case
それから、これは非常に有名な事件です
very very simple
とてもとてもシンプルです
let me say by the way
ところで言わせてください
That if you are interested
興味があれば
Interested in Game Theory
ゲーム理論に興味がある
You can next year on May 15th
来年は5月15日に開催できます
Attend a lecture at the Department of Political Science, National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学政治学部で講義を受講
That is Teacher Lin Zhemin
それは林哲民先生です
The topic he opened is called president
彼が開いたトピックは「社長」と呼ばれています
crime problem
犯罪問題
Mr. Lin Zhemin is in our building now
林哲民氏は今私たちの建物にいます
He is a graduate of the Department of Electrical Engineering
彼は電気工学科を卒業しています。
Then why did he study political science?
では、なぜ彼は政治学を学んだのでしょうか？
He shouldn't think the electrical engineering department is boring
彼は電気工学科が退屈だと思うべきではない
He should feel that the problem of political science
彼は政治学の問題だと考えるべきだ
funnier than a motor
比電機有趣
Then why is he so obsessed with this matter?
では、なぜ彼はこの問題にそこまで執着するのでしょうか？
presence dilemma
存在のジレンマ
because he said it was a very simple model
彼はそれが非常に単純なモデルだと言ったので
let's take a look
見てみましょう
We use this thing as a game theory case
これをゲーム理論の事例として使用します
Let's look at this below
以下でこれを見てみましょう
this thing
このこと
Let's say there are two people
二人の人がいるとしましょう
Two people
二人
Then each person has two strategies
その場合、各人には 2 つの戦略があります
one called
呼ばれた人
copyrightCooperate with each other
著作権相互協力
The other one is called defect
もう一つは欠陥と呼ばれるものです
defact means not to cooperate with the other party
不履行とは相手に協力しないことを意味します
So the strategy of the two people is the same
つまり二人の戦略は同じ
and what are those numbers in the middle
そして真ん中の数字は何ですか
The numbers in the middle are your payoff
真ん中の数字が報酬です
The higher the number, the better
数値が高いほど良い
so it's easy
だから簡単です
What we're going to look at now is to say
これから検討するのは、次のようなことです。
These two people if he
彼ならこの二人
itself has two strategies
それ自体には2つの戦略があります
Do you want to cooperate with each other?
お互いに協力してみませんか？
Do you want
欲しいですか
Then each state has four states, right?
そうすると、それぞれの州には 4 つの州がありますね。
Two to one two equals four
2 対 1 2 は 4 に等しい
Each state will give you some points
各州によっていくつかのポイントが与えられます
Then we now know that
それから私たちは今それを知っています
these two people
この二人
Of course he just wants to get the highest score
もちろん彼は最高のスコアを獲得したいだけです
it's easy
それは簡単です
then what would you choose
じゃあ何を選ぶ？
I should cover this first
これを最初にカバーする必要があります
No, there are three here
いいえ、ここには 3 つあります
Can't hide
隠せない
Actually I should do an experiment
本当は実験をしたほうがいいのですが
Don't ask, let's see who you will choose
聞かないで、あなたが誰を選ぶか見てみましょう
So this story turned out to have been written a long time ago.
つまり、この物語はずっと前に書かれたものであることが判明しました。
But who turned it into something that everyone can understand
でもそれを誰もが理解できるものに変えたのは誰ですか
It's John Nash's teacher
ジョン・ナッシュの先生です
Just John Nash in front of him, his teacher
彼の目の前には彼の先生であるジョン・ナッシュだけがいる
Because he turned it into a story that everyone can understand
誰もが理解できる物語にしてくれたから
What is this called? It's called a quarantine certificate
これは何と呼ばれますか? 検疫証明書と呼ばれます
OK now suppose there are two suspects
さて、容疑者が 2 人いると仮定します
they robbed the bank
彼らは銀行強盗をした
After being arrested, the police said whether they did
逮捕後、警察は「やったかどうか」と語った。
So cooperation means I say I didn't do it
だから協力ということは、私はやっていなかったと言うことだ
To betray the other party is to say that he has done it
相手を裏切ったら「やった」と言いなさい
The policeman is quarantine
警察官は隔離中です
So he can ask the same question to two people
それで彼は 2 人に同じ質問をすることができます
OK so what do you think your strategy is
さて、あなたの戦略は何だと思いますか
Do you want to betray each other?
お互いを裏切りたいですか？
you think you're gonna betray
裏切ると思ってるの？
I'm asking if anyone is nice
誰かいい人いるか聞いてる
Then you don't want to betray the other party's
それなら相手を裏切りたくないですよね？
just talk
ちょうど話
Otherwise I can't go on
そうしないと話が続けられない
You will have someone who doesn't want to betray the other party and choose the cooperate
相手を裏切りたくない人が協力を選ぶでしょう
How about, okay, hypothesize like this
そうですね、こんな仮説を立ててみてはいかがでしょうか
Let's say you don't sell out
売り切れないとしましょう
make you feel where your risk is
自分のリスクがどこにあるのかを感じさせる
You'd think you'd be betrayed by him, wouldn't you?
彼に裏切られると思うでしょう？
Do you understand where my problem is?
私の問題がどこにあるのか理解していますか？
That means you're going to wonder if he's going to betray me
ということは、彼が私を裏切るのではないかと思うことになるでしょう
if i don't betray him
私が彼を裏切らなければ
The premise is that he must not betray me
前提として彼は私を裏切ってはいけないということ
But do you really believe he won't betray you?
でも彼が裏切らないと本当に信じますか？
no why
いや、なぜ
this is human nature
これは人間の性質です
but i want to tell you
でも、あなたに言いたいのです
The basis of this human nature is the calculation of the game
この人間性の根幹はゲームの計算だ
let me tell you something
何か言わせてください
think about it
考えてみてください
You now have two strategies
これで 2 つの戦略ができました
Let's assume you are cooperating with defender
あなたがディフェンダーと協力していると仮定しましょう
Let's assume that the other party will cooperate with you
相手も協力してくれると仮定しましょう
Then do you want to betray him?
それであなたは彼を裏切るつもりですか？
Four points for betraying him, right?
彼を裏切った場合のポイントは 4 つですよね？
Then what
じゃあ何
if the other party betrays you
相手があなたを裏切った場合
more to betray him
もっと彼を裏切るには
So why did I just say that there is one of the most interesting aspects of the game?
では、なぜ私はこのゲームには最も興味深い側面の 1 つがあると述べたのでしょうか?
you have to be able to imagine what you want to do
自分が何をしたいのか想像できなければならない
to imagine what he would do
彼が何をするかを想像する
so feel weird
だから奇妙に感じる
i will betray him
私は彼を裏切るでしょう
he will betray me
彼は私を裏切るでしょう
right
右
so what is the end result
それで、最終的な結果は何ですか
so how many points will you end up with
それで最終的に何点取れるでしょうか
Is the result of 22 good?
22の結果は良かったでしょうか？
not good
良くない
This is a very interesting example
これは非常に興味深い例です
I'm going to use this as an example for someone who hasn't learned the game at all
ゲームをまったく学習していない人向けの例としてこれを使用します
That said, the funniest part of the game is here
つまり、このゲームの最も面白い部分はここにあります
22 He is the only one among the four results that does not belong to paradise optimal
22 4 つの結果の中でパラダイス最適に属さない唯一の人物です
What is paradise optimal
最適な楽園とは何ですか
how to define
定義方法
if a result can't be better
これ以上の結果が得られない場合
The result is paradise optimal
結果は楽園最適です
Then we now find that there are four results on the side of these four results
次に、これら 4 つの結果の横に 4 つの結果があることがわかります。
The only result that is not paradise optimal is mutual betrayal
最適な楽園ではない唯一の結果は相互の裏切りです
But he is the only balance
でも彼が唯一のバランスだ
Do you know what I'm talking about?
私が何のことを言っているか分かりますか？
That is to say if
つまり、もし
If you cooperate with each other, you can get three points.
みんなで協力すれば3ポイント獲得できます。
But why do you betray each other by two points?
しかし、なぜ2点差で裏切るのか？
so i'm thinking like this
そこで私はこう考えています
If you have time, watch the first episode of Wu Jiandao
時間があれば、呉建島の最初のエピソードを見てください。
that was a difficult choice
それは難しい選択でした
I just send a signal to the other party
相手に信号を送るだけです
will he believe it
彼はそれを信じますか
Even if he believes, will he be sentenced to me?
たとえ彼が信じたとしても、彼は私に処罰されるでしょうか？
Because Wu Jian said that he actually talked about a
呉建は実際にあることについて話したと言ったからです。
It's human
それは人間です
But it's also one of the most troubling issues of game theory.
しかし、これはゲーム理論の最も厄介な問題の 1 つでもあります。
How can I keep the other party from going out?
どうすれば相手が出て行かないようにすることができますか？
Very difficult
非常に難しい
Then this often happens
そうするとこういうことがよく起こる
often appear in our life
私たちの生活の中によく登場します
That is, if we both choose to trust each other
つまり、私たちがお互いを信頼することを選択した場合
Maybe I will be betrayed by the other party
もしかしたら相手に裏切られるかもしれない
So when I think about it I think it's still a bit new
だから、それについて考えると、それはまだ少し新しいことだと思います
I just sold him
私は彼を売ったばかりです
And at this time the police actually knew
そしてこの時点で警察は実際に知っていました
even if you call
電話しても
The other party will still sell you
相手はまだあなたを売りつけるでしょう
This has nothing to do with Information
情報とは関係ありません
Let's say I got a call from you saying
あなたから次のような電話があったとします。
i will cooperate with you
私はあなたに協力します
I'll send you a press number to say
プレス番号を送りますので、
let you see him betray him
彼が裏切るのを見させてください
Then there must be a conspiracy
それなら陰謀があるに違いない
remember me
私を覚えてますか
Of course we say from a statistical point of view
もちろん統計的な観点から言うと、
really do experiments
本当に実験をする
Of course we know that it means that most of the opponent's battles will be betrayed.
もちろん、それが相手の戦いのほとんどを裏切ることを意味することは承知しています。
But there are still a few
でもまだいくつかあるよ
Few people he didn't choose to betray each other
彼がお互いを裏切ることを選ばなかった数人の人々
Then this minority is worth studying.
そうすれば、この少数派は研究する価値があります。
why didn't you betray the other side
なぜ相手を裏切らなかったのか
Of course one of the simplest answers is in the laboratory
もちろん、最も単純な答えの 1 つは研究室にあります
know what i mean
わかる
Do an experiment, do an experiment in social science
実験をしてください、社会科学の実験をしてください
The biggest problem is that he has no external effects
最大の問題は、彼には外部効果がないことです
I'm in the lab and of course I can believe anything
私は研究室にいる、もちろん何でも信じられる
good
良い
sitting sitting sitting
座っている 座っている 座っている
right
右
good
良い
Yeah
うん
somewhat related
多少関係のある
Then I think it will be more betrayal
そうしたらもっと裏切られると思うよ
So it won't be like this two sessions
だから、この2つのセッションはそうではないだろう
this is the real game
これが本当のゲームだ
The game will take these factors you just won
ゲームでは、あなたが勝ったばかりのこれらの要素が考慮されます
all as unknowns
すべて未知のものとして
For example, I now assume
たとえば、今私が仮定するのは、
For example, the judge and the defendant
たとえば、裁判官と被告
he is playing a game
彼はゲームをしています
Then I would say that the judge's package matches the defendant's package
そうすれば、裁判官のパッケージは被告のパッケージと一致すると言えます
He is, say, XYD or something
彼はXYDか何かです
Then I will say under what conditions
じゃあどういう条件で言うと
The end result is that he'll plead guilty and negotiate.
最終的には彼は罪を認めて交渉することになる。
This game is actually not that difficult
このゲーム、実はそんなに難しくないんです
Why
なぜ
Because he must know the judge's attitude
裁判官の態度を知っているはずだから
The two sides do not know each other's attitude
双方はお互いの態度を知らない
That is, when a game is played
つまり、ゲームをプレイするとき、
it comes in various forms
それはさまざまな形で現れます
message is very important
メッセージはとても重要です
If I could somehow
なんとかできたら
let you know my attitude is this
私の態度がこれであることを知らせてください
It's actually too simple
実はシンプルすぎるんです
through a lawyer
弁護士を通して
can already let him know
すでに彼に知らせることができます
you just plead guilty
あなたはただ有罪を認めただけです
you can come out
出てもいいよ
Introspect, that's what it means
内省する、それが意味するところだ
So this game is actually not that difficult
ということで、このゲームは実はそれほど難しくないのですが、
So I think
それで私は思います
want
欲しい
right
右
meeting
ミーティング
i totally agree with you
完全にあなたと同意します
that is
あれは
In this case if you
この場合、あなたが
it shouldn't be what i want to talk about
それは私が話したいことではないはずです
I don't study law
私は法律を勉強しません
But I think from studying the law
でも、法律を勉強して思うのは、
have a point of view on this matter
この問題について見解を持っています
it is legal
それは合法です
OK the main problem is plea bargaining
OK、主な問題は司法取引です
there is something wrong with the system
システムに問題があります
Anyway
ともかく
simply speaking
簡単に言えば
When the judge made this decision
裁判官がこの決定を下したとき
If he thinks it's legal
彼がそれが合法だと思うなら
Will he care what voters are thinking
彼は有権者が何を考えているか気にするだろうか
Nope
いいえ
know what i mean
わかる
Because we usually judge
普通は判断するから
It's all prosecutors who want to present
出廷したいのは検察官ばかりだ
I'm going to sue this guy
この男を訴えるつもりだ
Then your proof is
そうするとあなたの証拠は
prosecutors decision
検察の決定
Judges can only rely on prosecutors
裁判官は検察官にしか頼れない
Bring the evidence to trial
証拠を裁判に持ち込む
so you want to do one thing
それであなたは一つのことをしたいのです
let's not talk about this case
この事件については話さないようにしましょう
we talk
私たちは話す
Black heart food is ready
ブラックハートの料理が完成しました
Why is black heart food innocent in the end?
なぜ黒心食品は結局無実なのでしょうか？
Of course, many people reacted directly and scolded the judge.
もちろん、多くの人が直接反応し、裁判官を叱責しました。
but you need to know
しかし、あなたは知る必要があります
it's a sequential game
それは連続ゲームです
As a result, the judge finally has to make a verdict
その結果、裁判官は最終的に判決を下さなければなりません
You must only look at the evidence presented by the prosecutor.
検察官が提出した証拠だけを見なければなりません。
So many people feel
とても多くの人が感じています
prosecutors are responsible
検察には責任がある
yes
はい
But the prosecutor
しかし、検察官は
what are you responsible for
あなたには何の責任がありますか
because it is based on what
それは何に基づいているからですか
According to the real security law
実質安全保障法によると
Who made the real security law?
本当の安全保障法を作ったのは誰ですか？
your elected status
あなたの選出ステータス
the people themselves
人々自身
What do you mean?
どういう意味ですか？
that is
あれは
It's a pretty complicated political issue
かなり複雑な政治問題です
Then why did the legislators make a real case that is difficult to implement?
では、なぜ議員らは実現が困難な現実の訴訟を提起したのでしょうか？
OK, then you will say that the legislator came from there before the election
OK、それでは議員は選挙前にそこから来たと言うでしょう
OK that's why I think
わかりました、だから私はこう思います
I can't talk about this anymore
これについてはもう話すことはできません
That is to say, in fact, many times
つまり、実際には何度も
people have only themselves to blame
人は自分自身だけを責めるべきです
For example, when you are in an election
例えば選挙のとき
How on earth did you unify that vote?
いったいどうやってその票を一本化したのでしょうか？
But I think that's changing
でもそれは変わりつつあると思う
i think it's changing
変わってきていると思う
At least many people will be dissatisfied with this verdict
少なくとも多くの人はこの判決に不満を抱くだろう
he should
彼がすべき
This Act of Act should be amended in the future
この法律は将来的に改正されるべきである
because you know you have problems at the source
原因に問題があることが分かっているからです
There will be problems later on
後々問題が起きるだろう
OK so all I can do is
OK、だから私にできることはこれだけです
You have to take a good look at your actual case law
実際の判例をよく見る必要がある
What are you listening in?
何を聞いているのですか？
the law of fact
事実の法則
if there is a judge
裁判官がいるなら
know that the court has a
裁判所には
is to be judged
裁かれることになる
yes
はい
right
右
Now this heaven about this political situation
さて、この政治情勢については天国です
I agree
同意します
many people like this
多くの人がこれが好きです
certainly
そうです
you know the biggest problem right now is
ご存知の通り、今最大の問題は
Your current law will make the final judgment difference
現在の法律が最終的な判断を変えることになる
this is the biggest problem
これが最大の問題です
Which means you're giving judges too much freedom to administer.
つまり、裁判官に裁量の自由を与えすぎているということだ。
He can also follow this exactly
彼もこれに正確に従うことができます
say he is guilty
彼は有罪だと言う
He can also say he is innocent
彼は無実だとも言える
because many details
多くの詳細があるため
but i think this is
でもこれはそうだと思う
yes
はい
So I think you still have to look at the content of the law at the source
したがって、やはり法律の内容を根源から見る必要があると思います。
but i believe many people
でも私は多くの人を信じています
Most people haven't read the real security law
ほとんどの人は本当の安全保障法を読んでいない
You're interested to see what exactly they stipulate
正確に何を規定しているのか知りたい
ok
Ok
Then we have to finish our topic
それでは、この話題を終わらせなければなりません
what to do
何をすべきか
Can everyone understand this?
皆さんはこれを理解できますか？
This is a very, very simple game
これはとてもとてもシンプルなゲームです
It's very simple, just two people
とてもシンプルです、二人だけです
Two people
二人
Only two strategies per person
戦略は 1 人につき 2 つまで
I can't imagine an easier game
これ以上簡単なゲームは想像できない
Simultaneous action
同時行動
It turned out to be a tragedy indeed
本当に悲劇になってしまった
that's why
それが理由です
4 is better than 3 3 is better than 2 2 is better than 1
4 は 3 より優れています 3 は 2 より優れています 2 は 1 より優れています
It is your cooperation points, how much benefit you get
どれだけお得になるかはあなたの協力ポイントです
Because I want people to understand right away
すぐに理解してもらいたいから
Because this may for example
なぜなら、これは例えば
You can use the reverse operation how long you will be locked up
どれくらいの時間ロックされるかを逆の操作で行うことができます
Then I just temporarily use the order of the size
あとはサイズオーダーを一時的に使うだけです
so that everyone can understand
誰もが理解できるように
I'm just saying the rules of the game are simple
ゲームのルールは簡単だと言っているだけです
Everyone wants to get the highest score
誰もが最高のスコアを獲得したいと考えています
But the final result was the penultimate time
しかし、最終結果は最後から2番目の時間でした
Right
右
i sure wish i had better get out
確かに出て行った方が良かったと思う
But when everyone counts like this
でもみんながこうやって数えると
would create a big problem
大きな問題が生じるだろう
is when each of you counts like this
あなた方一人一人がこのように数えたときです
The end result is really unwanted
最終結果は本当に望ましくないものです
but there is no way
しかし方法がありません
Then I would think that this is actually called
そうすれば、これは実際に呼ばれると思います
Later they became matchmakers
後に彼らは仲人になった
There's a reason it's called the Prisoner's Dilemma
囚人のジレンマと呼ばれるのには理由があります
You say that when we engage in social action
私たちが社会活動に参加するとき、あなたはそう言います
often in places where the prisoners are very ordinary
多くの場合、囚人がごく平凡な場所で
What kind of relationship do I want to maintain with the other party?
相手とどのような関係を保ちたいのか？
Very difficult
非常に難しい
Of course there are many people who are solving the criminal problem
もちろん刑事問題を解決している人もたくさんいます
The first one is you let him keep playing
1つ目は、彼にプレーを続けさせることです
Will the second round be better?
2ラウンド目は良くなるでしょうか？
Won't
しません
really won't
本当にしません
round three will be worse
ラウンド3はさらに悪くなるだろう
OK
OK
Because you have betrayed me before
あなたは前に私を裏切ったから
now don't i betray you
今、私はあなたを裏切らないでください
One way is you let him keep playing
一つの方法は、彼にプレーを続けさせることです
But don't know he knows when it will lift
でもそれがいつ解除されるか彼には分からない
it's an interesting inference
それは興味深い推論です
because when you
なぜなら、あなたがいるとき
I say this by the way
ちなみにこう言います
That is to say, when you are in this state
つまり、この状態にあるときは、
you have to keep playing with him
あなたは彼と遊び続けなければなりません
But when you're not sure when it's gonna end
でも、いつ終わるかわからないときは
he's going to be a really interesting thing
彼は本当に面白いことになるだろう
called culture
文化という
culture comes from here
文化はここから生まれる
what is culture
文化とは何ですか
Culture is a norm that everyone abides by
文化は誰もが遵守する規範です
And he's not legal
そして彼は合法ではない
That is to say when you talk to each other
つまり、一緒にいるとき
when you've been in this kind of trouble
このようなトラブルに陥ったとき
do you feel good
気持ちいい
I believe you first
まずあなたを信じます
Do you want to believe me too
あなたも私を信じたいですか
When I found out that it was okay
大丈夫だとわかったとき
Next round he will strengthen
次のラウンドでは彼は強化されるだろう
That is to say, you will find out whether to say betrayal or not to betray
つまり、裏切ると言うべきか、裏切らないべきかが分かることになる
It enhances the result of the previous round
前のラウンドの結果をさらに強化します
So if some people happen to
それで、もし何人かの人々がたまたま
They didn't think that much
彼らはそこまで考えていなかった
He said I just believe you
彼は、私はあなたをただ信じていると言った
then you also believe me
それならあなたも私を信じます
I feel it's ok
大丈夫だと思う
so it becomes a
だからそれは
often called culture
よく文化と呼ばれる
very funny
非常に面白い
The starting point of that culture is actually the game
その文化の原点は実はゲームだった
Although we are talking about culture all day long
私たちは一日中文化について話していますが、
But it's like not talking
でもまるで話してないような
a thing we often talk about
私たちがよく話すこと
That is why it does such a bad thing
だからこそあんな悪いことをするんだよ
because it's a criminal
犯罪者だから
why is this what he is talking about now
なぜ今彼はこれについて話しているのですか
why is it a criminal
なぜ犯罪者なのか
because it does bad things
悪いことをするから
ok
Ok
So what I'm saying is
それで私が言いたいのは、
The starting point of many problems is actually in this state
多くの問題の出発点は実はこの状態にあります
yes
はい
what's the problem
どうしたの
It is to be the lower body of the relationship between the various bodies
様々な身体の関係の下半身となること
yes
はい
that this is official
これが公式だということ
Should be from formal relationship fairness to
正式な関係の公平性から
They ended up with both being locked up
結局二人とも監禁されてしまいました
This is pushed from the individual to the collective
これは個人から集団へと押し上げられます
We start from a formal relationship
私たちは正式な関係から始まります
and then implement something
そして何かを実装する
this question is very good
この質問はとても良いです
Then I'll just tell you the following passage
それでは次の一節だけをお伝えします
Because you have asked the following question
次のような質問をしたので、
I really don't have enough time
本当に時間が足りない
I'll just jump
ただジャンプするよ
do you know who wrote this book
この本を誰が書いたか知っていますか
Leviathan
リヴァイアサン
yes
はい
his name is already on it
彼の名前はすでに載っています
is this person
この人ですか
Thomas Hoss
トーマス・ホス
why did he write this book
なぜ彼はこの本を書いたのか
We certainly can't say he invented the barter puzzle.
彼が物々交換パズルを発明したとは決して言えません。
no
いいえ
But his Revision
しかし彼の改訂版は
Theme of
のテーマ
The main argument is very similar to
主な議論は次のように非常に似ています
Revision
リビジョン
If I may, I can briefly summarize it like this
できれば簡単にまとめるとこんな感じです
Though I'm not thinking of testifying
証言するつもりはないけど
he has a very important concept
彼は非常に重要な概念を持っています
That is to say, through this book
つまり、この本を通じて、
You can see why sovereignty is necessary
主権がなぜ必要なのかがわかります
Sovereignty is otherwise necessary
それ以外の場合は主権が必要です
why what is sovereignty
なぜ主権とは何ですか
because
なぜなら
Hobbes he would describe a state of nature
ホッブズ氏は自然の状態について説明します。
what is the state of nature
自然状態はどうなっているのか
just two swaps
たった2回の交換
right
右
Then your two begging
それからあなたたち二人は懇願します
You can
あなたはできる
see the state of nature
自然の状態を見る
is what they will do
それは彼らがやることだ
He used a metaphor, which I think is very expressive.
彼は比喩を使いましたが、それは非常に表現力豊かだと思います。
Which means they all have swords in their hands.
つまり全員が剣を手に持っているということだ。
sword in hand
手に持った剣
He'll kill you when he gets a chance
彼は機会があればいつでもあなたを殺すでしょう
So the final result is
最終的な結果は次のとおりです
we just saw the previous one
先ほど見たばかりです
that neutral defect
その中立的な欠陥
betray each other
お互いを裏切る
So they are in a state
つまり、彼らはある状態にあります
it's a very bad state
とても悪い状態です
as a result of you protecting yourself
あなたが自分を守った結果
make you mistrust each other
お互いに不信感を抱かせる
right
右
So better results
より良い結果が得られるように
Let's take a look at the previous one
前回も見てみましょう
better result
より良い結果
It should be changed from two two to three three, right?
2 2 から 3 3 に変更する必要がありますね。
who can do such a thing
誰がそんなことできるの
So Hobbes he established his theory
そこでホッブズは理論を確立した
That is to say, who can
つまり、誰ができるのかというと、
Under the situation where everyone is against everyone
全員が全員に敵対する状況下で
This is the prisoner's problem
これは囚人の問題です
can cooperate with each other
お互いに協力できる
He said there is only one power
彼は言った、力は一つしかない
called advice
アドバイスと呼ばれる
distance
距離
This is the concept of sovereignty
これが主権の概念です
Then we from this point of view
それでは、この観点から私たちは
you can see this
これを見ることができます
From this point of view, we can compare
この観点から比較してみると、
you only need to know hobbes
ホッブズについて知っていればいいだけです
why is he so annoying
なぜ彼はそんなに迷惑なのですか
But why are you here today
でも、なぜ今日ここにいるのですか
still studying him
まだ彼を研究している
because he told us one thing
なぜなら彼は私たちに一つのことを言ったからです
politics is inevitable
政治は避けられない
i just wanted to say
ただ言いたかっただけです
i should hire an economist
経済学者を雇うべきだ
Study the Prisoner's Problem
囚人問題を研究する
how will they feel
彼らはどう感じるだろうか
that feeling might be
その気持ちはそうかもしれない
that is a special case
それは特殊なケースです
Really
本当
because i just
なぜなら私はちょうど
Such logic is completely consistent with
このようなロジックは以下と完全に一致しています
the rational logic used by economists
経済学者が使う合理的な論理
but then why did you say
でも、それではなぜ言ったのですか
Rational logic is a special case
合理的論理は特殊なケースです
So Hobbes already saw
つまりホッブズはすでに見ていた
this problem
この問題
He said that if there is no coercive person to come out
強制力のある人が出てこないなら、と彼は言った。
you on the handle
ハンドルの上のあなた
Swords in everyone's hands
剣はみんなの手に
when everything ends
すべてが終わるとき
you'll keep going
あなたは続けます
That society is in a
その社会は
state of war
戦争状態
So who can make
では誰が作れるのか
Swords in everyone's hands
剣はみんなの手に
wrap it up
急いでください
only one thing called country
国と呼ばれるものはただ一つ
so now everyone knows
だから今では誰もが知っています
what is the definition of country
国の定義は何ですか
Here we are
ここにいます
There are many definitions of country
国の定義はたくさんある
What do you think the definition of a country is?
国の定義は何だと思いますか?
Research is a thesis
研究は論文です
Yes, you said nothing wrong
はい、あなたは何も間違ったことは言っていません
What is a country? What is Weber's definition?
国とは何ですか?ウェーバーの定義は何ですか?
I just know the definition of country now
国の定義がやっとわかった
Of course many kinds
もちろん種類も豊富
That Max Weber from Germany
ドイツ出身のマックス・ウェーバー
Complicated. It's hard to say what subject he is in.
複雑です。彼がどのような主題に属しているのかを言うのは難しいです。
He said that the state is actually a partner of legal violence
彼は、国家は実際には法的暴力のパートナーであると述べた
Right, there should be nothing wrong with that, right?
そうですね、何も問題ないはずですよね？
He is a
彼は
Let him use force after legalization
合法化したら武力行使させろよ
Then come a system that restricts people's freedom
そして人々の自由を制限するシステムが登場する
called national state stop
国家停止と呼ばれる
Then you know it's a very paradoxical definition
そうすれば、それが非常に逆説的な定義であることがわかります
On the one hand, he can concentrate everyone's weapons in his hands
一方で、彼は全員の武器を自分の手に集中させることができます
much like the army
軍隊と同じように
army or police
軍隊か警察か
i can't imagine the army without guns
銃のない軍隊なんて想像できない
You can't imagine the police without guns
銃のない警察なんて想像できない
must be essentially a violence to them
それは本質的に彼らにとって暴力に違いない
But he is a legal violence
しかし、彼は法的な暴力です
Then this thing can help us answer
そうすれば、これは答えに役立ちます
Judgment problem its a solution
判断問題は解決策だ
As far as HOPPS it tells us that
HOPPS に関して言えば、
When everyone and everyone are in a state of mutual hostility
みんなとみんなが敵対関係にあるとき
And even if you want to cooperate with the other party
そして相手に協力したくても
when it ignores you
それがあなたを無視するとき
only one way
片道だけ
is you let a sovereign come out
あなたは主権者を出させますか？
Take all the knives in everyone's hands
全員の手にすべてのナイフを持たせて
Then say you don't fight now
それなら今は戦わないって言ってよ
because i can kill you both
二人とも殺せるから
So the state it is violent in nature
したがって、その状態は本質的に暴力的です
But its violence is with the consent of the people
しかし、その暴力は国民の同意を得た上で行われます
It's a hanging rail, isn't it?
吊り下げレールですね。
I make you agree
同意させます
I can take the sword from your hand
君の手から剣を奪えるよ
no way
とんでもない
We have to see the result
結果を見なければなりません
Then let me ask you one thing by the way
それから、ところで一つ聞いておきますが、
Do you know when the revision was written?
その改訂版がいつ書かれたか知っていますか?
when was distance soul written
『ディスタンス・ソウル』が書かれたのはいつですか
guess and guess
推測して推測して
16 then 17
16、それから17
Okay, okay, he should have published several versions of the performance he published.
わかった、わかった、彼は自分が出版したパフォーマンスのいくつかのバージョンを出版するべきだった。
1651 what happened in 1651
1651 1651年に何が起こったのか
A very important event happened in 1651
1651年に非常に重要な出来事が起こりました
1651 English Civil War ended
1651 年にイギリス南北戦争が終結
That Britain itself had a civil war that lasted for decades.
イギリス自体が何十年も続く内戦を抱えていたこと。
There were a lot of little battles, and later everyone called that period
小さな戦いがたくさんあった、そして後に誰もがその時代を呼んだ
Cyber War
サイバー戦争
So he was in a state where the war was over and he was writing this
つまり彼は戦争が終わった状態でこれを書いているのです
So he has very, very strong space-time
つまり、彼は非常に強力な時空を持っています
He told you that we went through the Civil War in England
彼はあなたに、私たちはイギリス南北戦争を経験したと言いました
We did see that the British people really wanted to kill each other
イギリス国民が本気で殺し合いを望んでいることが分かりました
And you can't say that the other party is malicious, no
相手に悪意があるとも言えませんし、
So your only recourse is to stop calling
したがって、唯一の手段は電話を止めることです
stop calling so
そう呼ぶのはやめてください
And let's not forget what happened in 1651
そして、1651 年が何だったのかを忘れないようにしましょう
It is the three years since the concept of the so-called Modern State came out.
いわゆる近代国家という概念が出てきてから３年。
I think these historical cases
これらの歴史的な事例は、
Actually it has its connection
実はそれには関係があるのです
has its connectivity
接続性があります
And don't forget
そして忘れないでください
what happened in 1649
1649年に何が起こったのか
In 1649 England did a crazy thing
1649年、イギリスはとんでもないことをした
They wrapped Chelster First around their heads
彼らはチェルスターファーストを頭に巻きました
know what i mean
わかる
Are you not interested in British history?
イギリスの歴史に興味はありませんか？
Don't know where the UK is?
イギリスがどこにあるのか知りませんか？
Should I have heard Chelster First?
最初にチェルスターを聞くべきだったでしょうか？
when he wrote that book
彼がその本を書いたとき
The UK happens to be in Common Wales
イギリスはたまたまコモンウェールズにある
The one in Cromwell
クロムウェルのもの
Columbware
コロンウェア
UK's Chelster First has been headbanded
英国のチェルスター・ファーストがヘッドバンドを巻かれた
Why is it tied up
なぜ縛られているのか
because everyone voted
みんなが投票したから
So when Chelster First is going to be tied up
それで、チェルスターファーストがタイになるときは
also gave a speech
もスピーチをしました
he said no way
彼はそんなはずはないと言った
this is what everyone means
これは誰もが意味することです
It's interesting
それは面白い
Because it's mostly parliament that's against the king
国王に反対しているのは主に議会だから
OK mostly congress is against the king
OK、ほとんど議会は国王に反対している
So everyone thinks it should be wrapped around the head
だから誰もが頭に巻くべきだと思う
From a symbolic point of view
象徴的な観点から
If he could put a king to death
もし彼が王を死刑にできるとしたら
Congress is very powerful
議会は非常に強力です
So actually we
それで実際に私たちは
When he returned to history
彼が歴史に戻ったとき
we probably know one thing
私たちはおそらく一つのことを知っています
If we look at British history
イギリスの歴史を見てみると
That is to say, Congress is very powerful.
つまり、議会は非常に強力であるということです。
then he can decide the king
そうすれば彼は王を決めることができる
to be beheaded
斬首される
then you say
それからあなたは言います
Huh? What about Chelst II?
え? チェルスト II はどうですか?
Where
どこ
Just his son
彼の息子だけ
Yes, his son's name is Chelst II
はい、彼の息子の名前はチェルスト2世です
just said
今言いました
Let that John Grant
ジョン・グラントにしましょう
The one that can go to the British Academy
英国アカデミーに通える人
where is he
彼はどこにいますか
he said where was he
彼はどこにいるのかと言いました
so
それで
he must exist somewhere, right?
彼はどこかに存在するはずですよね？
yes he is in france
はい、彼はフランスにいます
I think European royal families are very interesting
ヨーロッパの王室はとても興味深いと思います
they usually occur in a country
それらは通常、ある国で発生します
In times of trouble he fled to France
困難に陥ったとき、彼はフランスに逃亡した
because they are relatives
彼らは親戚だから
so he's in france
それで彼はフランスにいる
Then of course
それからもちろん
Something very important happened in England
とても重要なことがイギリスで起きた
It should be 1689
1689年のはずだ
That's called the Glorious Revolution
それを名誉革命と呼ぶ
What is the Glorious Revolution
名誉革命とは何ですか
You see these things are connected
これらはつながっていることがわかります
that is
あれは
when we feel a normal
私たちが普通だと感じるとき
When the government should be legal to have the tools of violence
政府が暴力の手段を合法的に持つべきとき
The composition of your government itself is very important
政府の構成自体が非常に重要です
You want to make the government itself unable to use its violence
政府自体が暴力を行使できないようにしたいのですね
Hence the concept of legalization
そこで合法化という概念が生まれました
So I think the core issue of political science is
したがって、政治学の中核問題は次のとおりだと思います。
A government cannot be free from violence
政府は暴力から自由ではいられない
The second is do you want to use this violence
2つ目は、この暴力を使いたいかどうかです
OK these are two things but related
OK、これら 2 つは関連していますが、
So I think we're probably seeing
だから私たちはおそらく見ていると思います
He MustHops he's in this historical situation
彼はマストホップ、彼はこの歴史的状況にいます
we still have a little time
まだ少し時間があります
Then how do we study that authority
では、その権威をどのように研究すればよいのでしょうか
I'll just talk about it
それについてだけ話します
So I do a little bit of a simple summary
そこで、少し簡単にまとめてみます
That means game theory, he studies war.
それはゲーム理論を意味し、彼は戦争を研究しています。
In fact, his essence is to study war
実際、彼の本質は戦争を研究することです
Research Dominance
研究Dominance
Then statistics he is hoping
それから彼が望んでいる統計
What's up
どうしたの
Statistics He hopes to learn the most things with the least cost
統計 彼は最小限のコストでより多くのことを学びたいと考えています
Then political science is the study of conflicts between people
そうすると、政治学は人々の間の争いを研究することになる
So the core issues of these three things are very close
つまり、これら 3 つの問題の中核は非常に近いものであるということです
But the method used is different
ただし、使用する方法が異なります
That just means that after the establishment of the modern state
つまり、近代国家が成立してからということになります。
Gradually the disciplines are separated
徐々に分野が分かれていきます
i can't imagine saying
言うことは想像できない
will ground it at that time
その時点で接地します
what kind of scientist is it
それはどんな科学者ですか
Its real identity is the person in the sales department
その正体は営業部の人
ok you say Thomas Hopes
オーケー、トーマス・ホープスって言うね
what is it
それは何ですか
it is everything
それがすべてです
nothing
なし
but that is in the modern country
でもそれは現代の国での話
when not yet established
まだ確立されていないとき
So after the establishment of the modern state
つまり、近代国家の成立後、
There are so-called disciplines
いわゆる規律があります
That's why we are so poor today
それが今日私たちがとても貧しい理由です
I'm still writing when I get home
家に帰ってもまだ書いてます
That means I must contribute
つまり私は貢献しなければならないということです
Political Semester Opens
政治学学期が開講
Otherwise, it would not be regarded as
そうでない場合は、次のようにみなされません。
One of the best virtuous people of this generation
この世代で最も高潔な人物の一人
Kidding
冗談
i mean
つまり
this is our tragedy
これは私たちの悲劇です
But what I'm going to say is
でも、私が言いたいのは、
this thing will make us
このことは私たちを作るでしょう
really have to reflect on one thing
本当に反省しなければならないことが一つある
Then we can now use
次に、使用できるようになりました
what we just talked about
私たちが今話したこと
Are you here to study political science?
政治学を勉強しに来たんですか？
Can
できる
ok, since we talk about political science and
さて、私たちは政治学の話をするので、
game theory and statistics
ゲーム理論と統計
If there is such a close relationship
そんなに密接な関係があるなら
let's see
どれどれ
what kind of things it can do
どのようなことができるのか
As an example
例として
Let's take this example
この例を見てみましょう
Devexche's Law
デベシュの法則
Mohist Devexche the French scholar
モヒスト・デヴェシュ フランス学者
he has a very simple definition
彼は非常に単純な定義を持っています
He said the electoral system affects the party system
同氏は選挙制度が政党制度に影響を与えると述べた
Don't forget that he said this in the 1950s
彼が1950年代にこう言ったことを忘れないでください
1950s
1950年代
We now feel that it is a very common sense thing
今ではそれがとても常識的なことだと感じています
but he said
しかし彼は言いました
If there is a constituency, he will only elect a winner
選挙区がある場合、彼は勝者のみを選出します
Just like Taiwan's single constituency system
台湾の小選挙区制と同じ
A single constituency in the two-vote system
二票制の小選挙区
When there is only one winner
勝者が1人だけの場合
votes for each of your constituencies
各選挙区に投票してください
will focus on the top two candidates
上位2候補に焦点を当てる
It's called the M plus E rule.
それは「M プラス E ルール」と呼ばれます。
M is District Magnitude
M は地区マグニチュードです
what did he say
彼が何を言ったの
If your current system is proportional representation
現在の制度が比例代表制の場合
It depends on how many places you have in the British election.
それはイギリスの選挙で何議席を獲得できるかによって決まります。
Proportional representation is good for multiparty
比例代表制は複数政党制に有利
Of course, there is another system that was used in France at that time.
もちろん、当時フランスで使用されていた別のシステムがあります。
Called two rounds of voting Round out
2回の投票が行われた
he said two rounds of voting were fun
彼は二回の投票が楽しかったと言いました
The effect on the party system of two rounds of voting is
2回の投票が政党システムに及ぼす影響は次のとおりです。
it won't be bipartisan
それは超党派ではないだろう
It won't be a true multiparty system either.
それは真の多党制でもないだろう。
He wants more than both parties
彼は双方以上のものを望んでいます
Why
なぜ
have you ever thought about this
これについて考えたことがありますか
why don't i ask you again
もう一度聞いてみませんか
ok
Ok
you go back to his core proposition
あなたは彼の核心的な提案に戻ります
His core proposition is a game problem
彼の中心的な提案はゲームの問題です
if we feel
私たちが感じたら
The core problem of an electoral system is
選挙制度の核心的な問題は、
How many people can be elected in a constituency
一つの選挙区で何人当選できるか
right
右
we'll actually talk now
実際に今から話しましょう
Taiwan's electoral system is very unfair to small parties
台湾の選挙制度は小政党にとって非常に不公平である
because of your constituency
あなたの選挙区のせいで
There is not only one seat in the British election
イギリスの選挙には議席は一つだけではない
So M is equal to 1
したがって、M は 1 に等しい
then you get a corollary
そうすれば当然の結果が得られます
When M is equal to 1
Mが1に等しいとき
Voters' votes will be concentrated in M ​​plus 1 is two
有権者の票はMプラス1が2に集中する
above the political party
政党の上にある
Well, there's some interesting mathematical corollary here.
さて、ここには興味深い数学的帰結があります。
This inference is actually part of the game
この推論は実際にはゲームの一部です
why don't i give my vote to the third candidate
第三の候補者に投票してみませんか
he will not go up
彼は上がらないでしょう
correct
正しい
then you have to figure it out
それならあなたはそれを理解する必要があります
why won't he come
なぜ彼は来ないのか
ok
Ok
So he said it himself
だから彼は自分で言ったんだ
When he taught this theory in the 1950s
1950年代に彼がこの理論を教えたとき
He said
彼は言った
Of course he didn't learn the game himself.
もちろん、彼は自分でゲームを学んだわけではありません。
But he talked about two effects
しかし彼は 2 つの効果について話しました
One is the mechanical effect
一つは機械的な効果です
Another psychological effect
もう一つの心理的影響
mechanical effect
機械的効果
Effect means different electoral systems
効果とは選挙制度の違いを意味する
it will have different thresholds
異なる閾値があるでしょう
M size is subject to change
Mサイズは変更になる場合がございます
He said your last party number
彼はあなたの最後のパーティー番号を言いました
number of valid candidates in other regions
他の地域の有効な候補者の数
will be related to M
Mと関係あるだろう
The second voter also looks at the so-called Mocanical Effect
2 番目の投票者は、いわゆるモカニカル効果にも注目します。
If voters say that the M in this constituency is too low
有権者がこの選挙区のMが低すぎると言ったら
He said I don't want to waste my vote
彼は私の投票を無駄にしたくないと言った
Everyone now knows what it means to waste your vote
投票を無駄にすることが何を意味するのか、誰もが知っています
as soon as we hear
聞いたらすぐに
7x keep Y right?
7x キープ Y ですよね？
That's what I mean
それが私の言いたいことです
That's called strategic voting
それは戦略的投票と呼ばれます
Everyone is very familiar with this
これについては誰もがよく知っています
On January 16, you will know what strategic voting is
1 月 16 日には、戦略的投票とは何かがわかります
And I know our strategic vote now
そして私は今、私たちの戦略的投票を知っています
very very complicated
とてもとても複雑
I still haven't figured out how to vote myself
自分で投票する方法がまだわかりません
anyway
ともかく
This thing affects everyone's life
このことはみんなの人生に影響を与える
But he talked about it in the 1950s
しかし、彼は1950年代にそれについて話しました
Then what we're going to ask now is
それでは、私たちがこれから尋ねることは、
This is a very, very famous definition in political science
これは政治学では非常に有名な定義です
Can he be studied?
彼は研究できるでしょうか？
Of course, when he brought up such a thing in the 1950s
もちろん、1950年代に彼がそのようなことを持ち出したとき、
you can't see any equation
方程式が見えない
he said it
彼はそれを言いました
I will say one thing by the way
ところで一つ言っておきます
that newton he wrote that
あのニュートンが彼はこう書いた
GBRVC is the original time of physics
GBRVC は物理学の本来の時間です
He also didn't use Equation
彼は方程式も使わなかった
ok
Ok
you should read that book
あなたはその本を読むべきです
That is, he just uses Hirao straight numbers like this
つまり、このように平尾のストレートな数字を使っているだけです
But there are many, many, many people behind him
でも彼の後ろにはたくさんの人がいる
testing his theory
彼の理論をテストする
This is Divac shape
これがディバック形状です
OK this is him
OK、これが彼です
that's st paul's church
それは聖パウロ教会です
It was a symbol of authority at the time
当時の権威の象徴だった
I don't know why he took this photo
なぜ彼がこの写真を撮ったのか分かりません
That is, he is higher than that authority
つまり、彼はその権威よりも上位です
should have that meaning
そういう意味があるはずだ
this is the expiration of the camera
これはカメラの使用期限です
ok
Ok
One of our most interesting questions is
私たちの最も興味深い質問の 1 つは、
Do you think the law of Divac shape is Low
Divac 形状の法則は低いと思いますか?
Is it a Low?
ローですか？
Because we usually talk about the laws of science
私たちは普段科学の法則について話しているので、
We usually use the word Low
私たちは通常「Low」という言葉を使います。
it is a law
それは法律です
But do you think its Low is Low?
しかし、その安値は低いと思いますか?
this is an interesting question
これは興味深い質問です
then let me tell a little story
それから少し話をさせてください
That is to say, this Divac shape itself
つまりこのDivacの形状そのもの
he did not study political science
彼は政治学を勉強しなかった
he never studied political science
彼は政治学を学んだことがない
Then what do you say he studied?
では、彼は何を勉強したと思いますか？
He studies law
他學法律
just call it lol
ただ電話してください（笑）
just kidding
冗談だ
do you know i'm kidding
私が冗談だと​​いうことを知っていますか？
this is no joke
これは冗談ではありません
it's true
それは本当です
he has a
彼が持っています
The one he just mentioned
彼が今言ったもの
How electoral systems affect party systems
選挙制度が政党制度に与える影響
He said it's called LOL
彼はそれを「笑」と呼ぶと言いました
Although he himself is a LOL
彼自身は大爆笑ですが、
well
良い
scholars
学者
but
しかし
he made a very important contribution
彼は非常に重要な貢献をした
He after World War II
彼は第二次世界大戦後、
He founded the Department of Politics in France
彼はフランスに政治省を設立しました
Formerly French Faculty of Politics
旧フランス政治学部
In fact, it is part of LOL
実際、それはLOLの一部です
because he tells you how to rule
彼は統治方法を教えてくれるから
In fact, some countries still
実際、一部の国では今でも
that is
あれは
In fact, political science is very close to law.
実際、政治学は法律に非常に近いものです。
As far as political science is actually the law department
政治学は実際には法学部です
or law school
または法科大学院
a branch at the bottom
一番下の枝
But what we talk about political science now is not
しかし、私たちが今政治学について話しているのはそうではありません。
So he created himself
そこで彼は自分自身を創造した
so-called political science in french
フランス語でいわゆる政治学
then of course we later
それからもちろん後で
After he dropped such a thing and came out
そんなもの落として出てきた後
Many people helped him correct
多くの人が彼の修正を手伝ってくれました
This fix is ​​itself a Test
この修正自体はテストです
The first one hides some so-called game models in it
最初のものには、いわゆるゲームモデルがいくつか隠されています。
For example, why should I vote strategically?
たとえば、なぜ戦略的に投票する必要があるのでしょうか?
If the political party knows that voters will vote strategically
有権者が戦略的に投票することを政党が知っている場合
how is it nominated right
どうやって正しく指名されるのか
This is an interactive process
これは対話型のプロセスです
if i knew you would piss me off
あなたが私を怒らせると知っていたら
do i still nominate
まだ指名しますか
Or is my nomination bogus?
それとも私の指名は偽物なのでしょうか？
do you know what i mean
分かりますか
I really want you to vote for someone else
ぜひ他の人に投票してほしいです
OK, especially the two-vote system for a single constituency
OK、特に小選挙区の2票制
very complicated
とても難しい
I may propose a false one in one constituency
一つの選挙区で虚偽の提案をするかもしれない
but i need your vote
でもあなたの投票が必要です
vote for another party
他の政党に投票する
We are now filled with such calculations
今私たちはそんな計算でいっぱいです
So funny
とても面白い
We are counting and he is counting
私たちは数えています、そして彼も数えています
Well, many people helped him calculate this later.
そうですね、多くの人が後で彼がこれを計算するのを手伝ってくれました。
Let his theory begin to formalize
彼の理論を定式化し始めましょう
start more like a game
もっとゲームらしく始める
And then a statistician comes in too
そして統計学者もやって来ます
what to do
何をすべきか
To see if his theory is true or not
彼の理論が真実かどうかを確かめるために
Yes, because his theory is very simple
はい、彼の理論は非常に単純なので、
Your electoral system affects your party system
選挙制度は政党制度に影響を与える
Let's take a look at a data I saw
私が見たデータを見てみましょう
this
これ
He means first pass the polls
彼が言いたいのは、まず投票に合格することだ
It's the British system
それはイギリスのシステムです
British and American systems
イギリスとアメリカの制度
That is to say, the constituencies are the same across the country.
つまり、選挙区は全国同じなのです。
first pass the polls
まず投票に合格する
Whoever gets the most votes is elected
最も多くの票を獲得した人が選出される
Elected with the highest number of votes
最多得票で当選
Then the two round system of TIS below
では、以下のTISの2ラウンド制
vote for two
2人に投票する
that france only recently voted
そのフランスはつい最近投票したばかりだ
two votes
2票
Right-wing voices on the ground
現場の右翼の声
The far right speaks loudly
極右は大声で言う
So it's Olon of the Socialist Party
社会党のオロンです
He's going to speak to his former political enemy Sacozi
彼はかつての政敵サコジ氏と話すつもりだ
I still let you go
私はまだあなたを手放します
Otherwise, it will be very troublesome if the extreme right is elected.
そうでないと極右が当選したら大変なことになる。
Because he is in many areas with strong votes of the Socialist Party
なぜなら彼は多くの分野で社会党の強い票を集めているからである。
They're all extreme rightists
全員極右主義者だよ
Relatively speaking, the highest vote
相対的に言えば、最も高い投票数
So he had to let the political party do the mobilization
そこで彼は政党に動員を任せなければならなかった
Sacozi please come out
サコジ出てきてください
do you know
あなたは知っていますか
This is the mobilization of a political party
これは政党の動員です
A 2 round system
2ラウンド制
The last one is of course PR
最後はもちろんPRです
Proportional representation
比例代表制
we see a very interesting thing now
今とても興味深いことが分かりました
Here is our observation paper
これが私たちの観察論文です
This is the result of a sampling
これはサンプルの結果です
then fate and obsession
それから運命と執着
fate is different from infatuation
運命は熱狂とは違う
The word of fate is all the papers add up
運命の言葉はすべての書類を合計することです
out of your observation
あなたの観察から
Midian is where you arrange
ミディアンはあなたが手配する場所です
like row from smallest to largest
最小から最大の行のようなもの
then take the middle one
それから真ん中のものを取ります
Then effectively shift
その後、効果的にシフトします
Effective positive file number it is actually an proxy
有効な正のファイル番号、実際にはプロキシです
The algorithm for the number of effective positive gears is
有効正ギア数のアルゴリズムは次のとおりです。
You take the square of the seat rate of each positive file
各ポジティブ ファイルのシート率の 2 乗を計算します。
Add it up and remove it with E
足してEで消す
a little complicated
少し複雑な
Just use E to divide a Sigma
シグマを割るには E を使用するだけです
Then the right side of Sigma
次にシグマの右側
It is the percentage of votes received by each positive file
各陽性ファイルが受け取った投票の割合です。
Sorry, the square of the seat rate
申し訳ありませんが、座席率の 2 乗です
OK will get a number
OK、番号を取得します
effective positive gear number
有効プラスギヤ数
Etecific number of parties
パーティの具体的な数
that's fun
それは面白い
We're looking at Midian
私たちはミディアンを見ています
Then I was shocked when I saw the result
そして結果を見てびっくりしました
At least the training is right
少なくともトレーニングは正しい
as it was in the 1950s
1950年代のように
writing this
これを書いている
But from my later data
しかし、その後のデータによると、
This 2011 data
この 2011 年のデータ
How much Midian is two
ミディアンは2といくらですか
That is to say, what am I doing here?
つまり、私はここで何をしているのでしょうか？
I know it has a theoretical expectation
理論的な期待があることはわかっています
Theoretical expectations from games
ゲームからの理論上の期待
說first pass to the post
說まずポストに渡す
it should form two gears
2 つのギアのうちの 1 つを形成する必要があります
I'm coming to check it out
確認しに来ます
Then this test
それからこのテスト
Of course, many countries are not in between
もちろん、多くの国はその中間ではありません
some countries
いくつかの国
Some countries have few political parties
政党がほとんどない国もあります
some a lot
いくつかたくさん
But its mystery is two
しかし、その謎は2つあります
so we know
だから私たちは知っています
DVX he did a thing
DVX 彼は何かをした
He uses a very simple pattern
彼は非常に単純なパターンを使用しています
tell us one thing
一つだけ教えてください
Then this thing can be verified
そうすればこのことは検証できる
I will testify for him now
今から彼のために証言します
I see it like this
こう見えます
Let's look at PR again
PRをもう一度見てみましょう
the bottom one
一番下のもの
Propulsion Rune Sensation 3.46
推進ルーンセンセーション 3.46
What is the value
価値とは何ですか
some countries may have many
いくつかの国には多くのものがあるかもしれません
Some countries have a high number of medical places
医療機関の数が多い国もあります
relatively low
比較低
But he will not be two long values
しかし、彼は2つの長い値にはなりません
very interesting
とても興味深い
TRS
TRS
Why 2.24
なぜ 2.24
Everyone never thought about this kind of problem
誰もがこの種の問題について考えたことはありません
that's a simple reason
それは単純な理由です
The so-called Turon System means
いわゆるトゥロンシステムとは、
two rounds of voting
2回の投票
two rounds of voting means
2回の投票手段
let's see the first round
最初のラウンドを見てみましょう
Is there anyone more than half
半分以上の人はいますか
If there are more than half of the people, he will be elected
国民の過半数が多ければ彼は選出されるだろう
but usually
しかし、通常は
under this selection
この選択の下で
You're gonna hope there's no one in the first round
最初のラウンドに誰もいないことを願うでしょう
Right
右
so you just
だからあなたはただ
There will be a bunch of parties in the first round
最初のラウンドではたくさんのパーティーが開催されます
Then see who's in the top two in the first round
次に、誰が最初のラウンドで上位 2 人になるかを確認します
do the second round
2ラウンド目をやる
what would you do if you were young
あなたが若かったら何をしますか
If you are a small party, now if Taiwan changes to
あなたが小さな政党であれば、今、台湾が次のようになれば
From single constituency to two-vote system
小選挙区から二票制へ
For example, a two-round voting system
たとえば、2ラウンド投票システム
what will you do
あなたは何をしますか
Of course you will threaten the big party
もちろん、大きなパーティーを脅すでしょう
So let's look at one thing now
それでは、ここで 1 つのことを見てみましょう
first round of voting
第一回投票
OK is comparing who is the top two
OK、誰が上位 2 人であるかを比較します
into the second round, right?
第二ラウンドに入りますよね？
So his competition is two
したがって、彼の競争相手は2人です
So his effective party count will be more than two
したがって、彼の有効パーティ数は 2 つ以上になります。
That's it
それでおしまい
do you mean to me
私に言ってるの？
That is because of your two rounds of voting
それはあなたの2回の投票のおかげです
so that small parties have a chance
小さなパーティーにもチャンスがあるように
Although he does not have majority support
彼は過半数の支持を得ていないにもかかわらず、
But he has a chance to advance to the second round
しかし、彼には2回戦に進むチャンスがある
so he can maintain a certain
そうすれば彼はある一定のことを維持できる
The existence of small parties
小さなパーティーの存在
But the small party will not be too many
しかし、小規模なパーティーはあまり多くはありません
And two rounds of voting have one
2 回の投票で 1 回の投票が行われます
very interesting effect
非常に興味深い効果
He will make it necessary for political parties to cooperate
彼は各政党の協力を必要とするだろう
Why
なぜ
because it's simple
シンプルだから
because you don't cooperate
あなたが協力しないから
you will lose the second round
2回戦で負けてしまいます
So the French think they
それでフランス人はこう考えます
their nationality is strange
彼らの国籍は奇妙だ
not surprising
驚かない
because you use two rounds of voting
2ラウンドの投票を使用するため
french say
フランスの言う
Hate each other but I love him so much
お互い嫌いだけど、私は彼をとても愛している
it's not surprising
驚くことではない
right
右
I said that's how you vote
そうやって投票するって言ったよ
i hate you now hate the key
私はあなたが嫌い​​です、今はキーが嫌いです
but two weeks later
しかし2週間後
we both made it to the second round
私たちは二人とも二回戦に進みました
I have to cooperate with you
私はあなたに協力しなければなりません
That's it
それでおしまい
Well, the good thing is that no one stays here.
まあ、良かったことは、ここに誰も留まらないことです。
really not
本当にありません
ok
Ok
That is to say, the electoral system
つまり選挙制度は
will depend on your culture
あなたの文化に依存します
But which one affects which
しかし、どれがどれに影響するか
that is
あれは
issues we can't discuss right now
今は議論できない問題
good
良い
So this is a very simple definition
これは非常に単純な定義です
that is
あれは
our 1950s
私たちの1950年代
someone throws this thing
誰かがこれを投げます
Then the mechanism behind
次に、背後にあるメカニズム
yes
はい
Actually
実際
median voter
投票者の中央値
extension of
の延長
That is to say, we can derive a law of M plus E
つまり、M プラス E の法則を導き出すことができます。
Then the key involved here
次に、ここに関係するキー
Voters will vote strategically
有権者は戦略的に投票する
Political parties will also strategically nominate
政党も戦略的に指名するだろう
Then he had a very clear prediction
それから彼は非常に明確な予測をしました
He said that if it was a unitary electoral system
もし統一選挙制度だったらと彼は言った
will form a two-party system
二大政党制を形成するだろう
Sorry if it's the deputy director election
副部長選挙だったらごめんなさい
In the case of proportional representation
比例代表制の場合
multi-party system
マルチパーティシステム
Then what
じゃあ何
DIS will be one of the two
DISは2つのうちの1つになります
It's about 2 o'clock
2時くらいです
what we see now is
私たちが今見ているのは
It is right
それは正しいです
So this is a good example
これは良い例です
I'll go back
戻ります
the problem i started with
私が始めた問題
What the hell is political science doing?
政治学は一体何をしているのでしょうか？
we probably know one thing now
私たちはおそらく今、一つのことを知っています
That is to say, political science is actually different from what everyone thinks now.
つまり、政治学というのは、実は今みんなが考えているものとは違うんです。
It seems to have nothing to do with politics
政治とは関係ないようです
actually its source
実はそのソース
next time maybe you can tell your friends
次回はお友達に教えてもいいかもしれません
statistics from political science
政治学からの統計
He said you were crazy
彼はあなたは気が狂っていると言った
I tell you why it's called statistics
なぜそれが統計学と呼ばれるかを説明します
what does that mean
どういう意味ですか
you don't know right
あなたは正しく知りません
To tell you statistics is to measure your country
統計を伝えることはあなたの国を測ることです
I hope someone from the statistics office will come today
今日は統計局から誰か来てくれるといいのですが
yes
はい
I don't know if you talked about the origin of the word
言葉の由来について話したかどうかはわかりませんが、
But that is a very real problem
しかし、それは非常に現実的な問題です
The second question is to say
2番目の質問はこう言うことです
does it have anything to do with the game
ゲームと何か関係がありますか
of course
もちろん
Because it's part of the nature of politics that I want to win
勝ちたいのは政治の性質の一部だから
do you know what i mean
分かりますか
What do you hear most often now?
今一番よく聞くことは何ですか?
who will win
誰が勝つ
Right
右
then how do i know i will win
じゃあどうやって勝てるかわかるの？
I see polls
世論調査を見ます
Who will win is the question of the game
誰が勝つかがゲームの問題だ
polls are statistics
世論調査は統計です
Of course we know that the so-called polls
もちろん、いわゆる世論調査が行われていることは知っています。
The current polls show that most of them are electric houses
現在の世論調査では、そのほとんどが電気住宅であることが示されています
not very accurate
あまり正確ではありません
We certainly have some people who do very clear polls
確かに非常に明確な世論調査を行う人が何人かいます
He can't see it in the media
彼はメディアではそれを見ることができない
But I think basically Taiwan's polls
でも基本的に台湾の世論調査はそうだと思う
has his credibility
彼の信頼性はある
So here we know one thing
ここで私たちは一つのことを知っています
It is said that political science is a very old science
政治学は非常に古い科学だと言われています
It is closely related to the establishment of the modern state
近代国家の成立と密接に関係している
So we know that like statistical games
つまり、統計ゲームのようなものであることがわかります
had a close relationship with it
それと密接な関係があった
OK, let's make another simple conclusion.
さて、もう一つ簡単な結論を出しましょう。
Sorry
ごめん
then turn around
それから振り向く
What questions do you think of when you look at our education system in Taiwan?
台湾の教育制度を見るとどんな疑問が浮かびますか?
my first question is
私の最初の質問は
they will ask me this question
彼らは私にこの質問をするでしょう
politics is not science
政治は科学ではない
I also thought about this question for a long time
私もこの質問について長い間考えました
In fact, it's useless for me to tell my mother.
実際、母に言っても無駄です。
Because she still doesn't know what statistics are
彼女はまだ統計が何なのかを知らないから
She still doesn't know which word statistics is
彼女は統計という言葉が何なのかをまだ知りません
But I think a lot of people have this idea
でも、この考えを持っている人は多いと思います
then i think we can imagine
それなら想像できると思います
If in the US or Europe
アメリカやヨーロッパにいる場合
Japan I don't know
日本は分かりません
This problem should not be that serious
この問題はそれほど深刻ではないはずです
for example
例えば
I don't know how American high school students choose courses
アメリカの高校生がどうやってコースを選ぶのかわからない
But they should not be grouped
しかし、それらをグループ化すべきではありません
Then I don't know why Taiwan has to be grouped
では、なぜ台湾をグループ化する必要があるのか​​わかりません
Then the last math is a group
そして、最後の数学的善は集合です
Mathematics is not good is another group
数学が苦手な人は別のグループです
that's terrible
それはひどい
In fact I know a lot of people who read
実際、私は読んでいる人をたくさん知っています
The so-called leaving the mouth is very painful
いわゆる口を離れることは非常に苦痛です
They obviously like reading literature
彼らは明らかに文学を読むのが好きです
So you say literature should not study mathematics?
では、文学は数学を勉強すべきではないと言うのですか？
wrong
間違い
math is important
数学は重要です
math is great
数学は素晴らしいです
don't know what i'm talking about
何を言っているのか分かりません
that is
あれは
We group students like this
学生をこのようにグループ化します
Actually it's not good
実は良くないんです
because there are some problems
いくつか問題があるので
In fact, it is not a problem of the subject itself.
実際、それは主題自体の問題ではありません。
It's a question of how the teacher teaches
先生の教え方の問題です
Look, I saw a lot of people nodding
ほら、たくさんの人がうなずいているのが見えた
right? we all suffer from it.
そうでしょう? 私たちは皆、それに苦しんでいます。
right
右
speak louder, yes
もっと大きな声で話してください、はい
and then i thought that was
そしてそれはそうだと思いました
RESPONSIBILITIES FOR OUR EXAMINATION SYSTEM
私たちの試験システムに対する責任
Why does it make some people feel like saying
なぜ一部の人はこう言いたくなるのでしょうか？
I'm not good at math, so I might as well go to school
私は数学が苦手なので学校に行ったほうがいいかもしれません
wrong
間違い
At least not in political science, and not in sociology either.
少なくとも政治学や社会学ではそうではない。
Why do you have to do mathematics when you read Lizhu? How can there be such a thing?
『李朱』を読むときに、なぜ数学をしなければならないのですか? どうしてそんなことがあり得るのでしょうか?
I think it's a lot of distractions
気が散ることが多いと思います
Actually, I'm not very good at math.
実は私は数学があまり得意ではありません。
so there is no necessary relationship
だから必要な関係はない
I think it's because people's lives are inherently complicated.
それは人間の人生が本質的に複雑だからだと思います。
Sometimes we need to use specific disciplines
場合によっては、特定の分野を使用する必要がある
some specific technology this nothing
特定のテクノロジー、これは何もありません
I think of course we now reflect on
もちろん今は反省していると思います
Taiwan's education itself has some problems
台湾の教育自体にも問題がある
I don't know if it's a little bit better now
今は少し良くなったかどうかはわかりませんが、
or more serious i don't know
あるいはもっと深刻なことはわかりません
listen to your opinion
あなたの意見を聞いてください
Then I will talk about this place first today
それでは今日はまずこの場所について話します
because sorry for more than a little time
少し長くなってごめんなさい
There's still a little time and I hope you can ask questions
まだ少し時間があるので質問していただければと思います
Teach the player Teach the player
教牌手 教牌手
Ask Professor Lin
リン教授に聞く
ask one about that
それについて誰かに聞いてください
host
ホスト
practice until you can
できるまで練習する
I would say
私なら言います
Excuse me
すみません
Ask you something about politics
政治について質問してください
continue
続く
How accurate are the polls about our current elections in Taiwan?
台湾の現在の選挙に関する世論調査はどの程度正確ですか?
I should recommend you the paper I wrote
私が書いた論文をあなたに勧めるべきです
Comparing the Accuracy Obtained by Different Survey Methods
さまざまな調査方法で得られた精度を比較する
very very accurate
非常に非常に正確
I will tell you a little story
ちょっとした話をします
Last year's nine-in-one election
昨年の9対1の選挙
We made a very simple game
とてもシンプルなゲームを作りました
We asked three groups of people to do the polls before the election
私たちは 3 つのグループの人々に選挙前に世論調査を行うよう依頼しました
Then ask them to write down how many votes Ke Wenzhe will get
次に、柯文哲氏が何票獲得するかを書いてもらいます。
Write it down and ask them to seal it
それを書いて封印してもらいます
then send me
それから私を送ってください
and then announced after election
次に選択して明らかにします
it's interesting
それは面白い
it's an interesting experiment
興味深い実験です
Then, of course, the predictions of the three people are all over 52%.
すると、当然のことながら3人の予想はいずれも52％以上。
is correct
正しい
But there is a group where he conducts polls
しかし、彼が世論調査を実施するグループがある
then i was taken aback
それから私はびっくりしました
I was at the time we had a sort of speech
私たちはある種のスピーチをしていたときでした
just three people here
ここには3人だけ
I am the host
私がホストです
i don't know what the answer is
答えがわかりません
I only see one person laughing
笑っている人が一人だけ見える
should be very accurate
非常に正確であるはずです
Once opened, almost the same
開けてみるとほぼ同じ
how does he do
彼はどうしていますか
The question we have to ask is how does he
私たちが尋ねなければならない質問は、彼がどのようにして
He was clearly before the election
彼は明らかに選挙前だった
That means polls can no longer be released
つまり、世論調査はもう公開できなくなります
Then he used his method
それから彼は自分の方法を使いました
He just used traditional polling methods
彼は従来の投票方法を使用しただけです
He goes to political map
彼は政治地図に行きます
he didn't spend a lot of money
彼はあまりお金を使いませんでした
but his answer
しかし彼の答えは
when it is opened
開いたとき
clap your hands again
もう一度手をたたきます
Because the representative said it was really accurate
担当者が本当に正確だと言っていたので
because of last year's election
去年の選挙のせいで
not a good election to predict
予測するには良い選挙ではない
We know Ke Wenzhe will probably win
柯文哲氏がおそらく勝つことはわかっています
But I didn't expect him to win so much
でもこんなに勝つとは思わなかった
And he not only predicts the polls
そして彼は世論調査を予測するだけではありません
is almost killing two percentage points
ほぼ 2 パーセントポイントを殺しつつあります
That is to say, it seems to be 57.9 and 57.7
つまり57.9と57.7らしいです。
so close
とても近い
Then he connects each constituency
それから彼は各選挙区を結びます
Turnout was exactly as predicted
投票率はまさに予想通りだった
almost the final answer
ほぼ最終的な答え
how did he do it
彼はどうやってそれをしたのか
Then he did something on the spot
それから彼はその場で何かをしました
He said
彼は言った
Now everyone knows that polls can be pretty accurate
今では世論調査がかなり正確であることは誰もが知っています
will you do the poll with me
私と一緒にアンケートをしませんか
nobody
誰でもない
I do not know why
何故かはわからない
It should be a good business
良いビジネスになるはずだ
Because he needs a lot of people to help him poll
投票に協力してくれる人がたくさん必要だから
Finally, someone said
最後に誰かが言いました
I can come and try
来て試してみることができます
His teacher must be very good at earth science
彼の先生は地球科学がとても得意なはずです
anyway
ともかく
Then the politics students don't know what you're doing
そうすると政治学生は君が何をしているのか分からない
In fact, polls can be very accurate
実際、世論調査は非常に正確です
Then that teacher is a teacher in the Department of Politics
じゃあその先生は政治学科の先生ですね
So I think the polls must have a way
だから世論調査には何らかの方法が必要だと思う
That is to say, how do you pump the pressure?
つまり、どうやって圧力をかけるのでしょうか？
Then how do you get your answer
ではどうやって答えを得るのか
absolutely impossible to call
電話するのは絶対に不可能
It shouldn't be that simple
そんなに単純なはずはない
You call and ask him who you want to support
あなたは彼に電話して誰をサポートしたいかを尋ねます
not so simple
そんなに単純ではない
Let him do the political map
彼に政治地図を作らせよう
That is to say, you have to look at each constituency
つまり選挙区ごとに見ていく必要がある
who did he vote for
他以前投誰
Then you have to weight
それから重さを量らなければなりません
then you just ask
それからあなたはただ尋ねます
OK
OK
The result is very clear
結果は非常に明確です
And I know his predictions are right every time
そして私は彼の予測が毎回正しいことを知っています
so I can report a thing to
だから私は何かを報告することができます
Polls can be accurate
世論調査は正確である可能性がある
But it's not the polls you hear all the time
しかし、それはいつも聞かれる世論調査ではありません
Just use that as a reference
あくまで参考として使ってください
he has a little fun
彼は少し楽しいです
But there are actually people polling
でも実際に投票してる人いるんだよ
he may not let you know
彼はあなたに知らせないかもしれません
Come
来て
joke
ジョーク
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you, teacher
ありがとう、先生
i feel like i want
欲しい気がする
Come
来て
of
の
fact area of ​​objective experience
客観的経験の事実領域
make decisions
決定する
But the source of decision-making power
しかし、決断力の源は
Is it normal Italian in general?
全体的には普通のイタリア語でしょうか？
The Genetic Facts of the Common Italian in Tradition
伝統における一般的なイタリア人の遺伝的事実
then this is us
それならこれが私たちです
Where modern stereotypes find it unscientific
現代の固定観念が非科学的だと考えるところ
Because the modern age has changed
現代は変わってしまったから
What do you think is science
科学とは何だと思いますか
not saying what i feel
私が感じていることを言わない
But generally our current mainstream stereotypes
しかし、一般的に、現在の主流の固定観念は
It seems that science is more like
科学はもっと似ているようです
Physics and Mathematics
物理学と数学
It is more empirically verifiable
より経験的に検証可能です
do you think physics is science
物理学は科学だと思いますか
It's all science
それはすべて科学です
What is the core concept of physics
物理学の核となる概念は何ですか
It's just some meaning of philosophy
それは哲学の単なる意味です
have you ever seen an atom
原子を見たことがあるか
no i'm kidding
いや、冗談だよ
mean to say
言う意味
Actually, let's talk about modern politics
実は現代政治について話しましょう
there are many parts
たくさんの部分があります
some part is to talk to voters
一部は有権者と話すことだ
for votes
投票のために
that's called a public servant
それを公務員といいます
That's a lot of bureaucrats
官僚が多いですね
the bureaucracy itself
官僚制そのもの
It is the industry of a modern country
それは近代国家の産業です
you will find that many people
たくさんの人がいることがわかるでしょう
His position will not be because of whom
彼の地位は誰のせいではない
change in power
権力の変化
OK
OK
so i think you should watch
だから見るべきだと思う
which department of the government
政府のどの部門ですか
Actually I feel modern
実はモダンな感じがするんです
part of the bureaucracy is very precise
官僚制度の一部は非常に正確です
it knows what its subjects think
被験者が何を考えているかを知っている
Because now especially in the era of social media
なぜなら今は特にソーシャルメディアの時代だから
There are a lot of ways that they can learn what people are thinking
人々が何を考えているかを学ぶ方法はたくさんあります
It's just that the biggest problem with the bureaucracy is that
ただ、官僚機構の最大の問題は、
they probably know it's the right thing to do
彼らはおそらくそれが正しいことだと分かっているだろう
dare not speak to him
あえて彼に話しかけないでください
know what i mean
わかる
This is a problem with the political system itself
これは政治制度そのものに問題がある
that is to say some politicians
つまり一部の政治家は
Let's just talk about it, Shi An Fa
それについて話しましょう、シ・アン・ファ
Are you sure that's the only version?
それが唯一のバージョンですか?
No, but why did this version pass in the end?
いいえ、しかし、なぜ最終的にこのバージョンが通過したのでしょうか?
This is a matter of legislative politics
これは立法政治の問題だ
There are many elements in politics
政治には色々な要素がある
There are some ingredients that they don't care about at all
全く気にしていない成分もある
They just make it acceptable
彼らはそれを許容できるようにしているだけです
their argument is fine
彼らの議論は大丈夫だ
But there are still some of them
しかし、まだいくつかあります
Because a very important condition for your modern country to run is
なぜなら、近代国家が運営されるための非常に重要な条件は、
you must know
あなたが知っている必要があります
Let's say we're going to talk
話し合うとしましょう
Guest writer, he is going to the ruling platform, not the ruling
ゲストライター、彼は判決ではなく判決プラットフォームに行く予定です
he's going to manage
彼はなんとかなるだろう
To him it's domination
彼にとってそれは支配だ
He is going to manage Taipei City
彼は台北市を管理する予定です
the purpose behind him
彼の背後にある目的
very important
とても重要な
I give a simple example
簡単な例を挙げます
For example, he set up a bus stand
たとえば、彼はバス停を設置しました
Just to tell you what time it is
今何時かを伝えるために
that is definitely not an easy thing
それは決して簡単なことではありません
definitely not an easy thing
決して簡単なことではありません
For example, he said that there is a charge for parking now.
たとえば、現在駐車場は有料だそうです。
It's definitely not an easy thing
それは確かに簡単なことではありません
He's going to do a thorough investigation on that one.
彼はそれについて徹底的な調査をするつもりだ。
only possible
可能だけ
That is to say, there is this characteristic
つまりこんな特徴があるのです
But with some governments he may
しかし、一部の政府では、彼は、
I don't pay much attention to this
これにはあまり注意を払いません
But I think democracy is a
しかし、民主主義とは、
The good thing is he can make that
良いのは彼がそれを実現できることだ
Does not rely on modern technology
最新のテクノロジーに依存しない
Then the reign of chaos will come down one day
そして混沌の統治はいつか崩壊するだろう
or his party
または彼のパーティー
I want to ask a question is
質問したいのは、
ask the teacher here
ここの先生に聞いてください
i ask a question
質問をする
what you just said
あなたが今言ったこと
about statistic
統計について
Does this statistic include it?
この統計にはそれが含まれていますか?
so-called information
いわゆる情報
know how to draw
絵を描く方法を知っています
including taking pictures
写真撮影も含めて
including control over the number of merging
マージ回数の制御を含む
I think this is also a statistic
これも統計だと思います
as a game
ゲームとして
He has to understand such a distribution
彼はそのような分布を理解する必要がある
Then this theory can be considered as this
すると、この理論は次のように考えることができます
Are you within the scope of today's discussion?
今日の議論の範囲内ですか？
Or even including Ling Nai to formulate this notoriety law
あるいは、この悪名法を制定するためにリン・ナイを含めることさえできる
He put all this plant except Sweden
彼はスウェーデン以外のこの植物をすべて置きました
All controlled by his notoriety
すべては彼の悪名によって支配されている
Then this definitely has very accurate statistic information
これには間違いなく非常に正確な統計情報が含まれています
That is, two things never had the same name.
つまり、2 つのものが同じ名前を持つことはありませんでした。
When the third type appears, the
3 番目のタイプが表示されると、
So from the game you just talked about
それで、あなたが今話したゲームから
Spread all the way to species dispersal to map
種の分散から地図までずっと広がる
ask the teacher something like this
先生にこのように質問してください
Is there any discussion in political science? Thank you
政治学で何か議論はありますか? ありがとうございます
should say so
そう言うべきだ
Our political science is no longer directly dealing with this issue
私たちの政治学はもはやこの問題を直接扱っていません
But I think for a modern country
しかし、私は近代国家について考えます。
very important thing
とても重要なこと
Do you know one thing
一つ知っていますか
When Japan colonized Taiwan
日本が台湾を植民地化したとき
who will he send first
彼は誰を最初に送りますか
two kinds of scholars
二種類の学者
The first was an anthropologist
最初は人類学者でした
The second one is I don't know what academic
2つ目は、何の学問か分かりません
but he botanist
しかし彼は植物学者です
That is to say
つまり
When the Japanese ruled Taiwan
日本が台湾を統治していた頃
He did two very important things
彼は 2 つの非常に重要なことを行いました
For a modern country
近代国家のために
everyone has interaction
誰もが交流を持っています
Every number gets better
すべての数字が良くなります
Do you understand what I mean?
私の言っている意味が分かりますか？
Only when he understands who he controls
彼が誰をコントロールしているのかを理解した場合にのみ、
and where do these people live
そしてこの人たちはどこに住んでいますか
how many natural resources
天然資源はどれだけあるのか
he is more sure
彼はもっと確信がある
because he is an outsider
彼は部外者だから
so you'll find that a lot of things are said
それで、たくさんのことが言われていることがわかります
he did it very thoroughly
彼はそれをとても徹底的にやりました
That's statistics
それは統計です
That is to say, how do you make
つまり、どうやって作るのかというと、
you in a short time
あなたはすぐに
A system capable of setting up an account
アカウントを設定できるシステム
You will let the land you control
あなたは土地を自分が支配できるようにするでしょう
Every number slowly gets better
すべての数値がゆっくりと改善されます
he must be very thorough
彼はとても徹底しているに違いない
are you doing these things
あなたはこれらのことをしていますか
OK, of course it means you're going to research
OK、もちろん調査するという意味です
This is actually the history of statistics
実はこれが統計の歴史なのです
How does it start with something like this
どうやってこんな事から始まるんだろう
Then you find out that Japanese people do things like
すると、日本人は次のようなことをすることがわかります。
he didn't invent it himself
彼は自分で発明したわけではない
Europeans do it
ヨーロッパ人はそれをやる
Europeans are going to occupy other places
ヨーロッパ人は他の場所を占領するつもりだ
occupy elsewhere
他の場所を占領する
he should know before
彼は前に知っておくべきだった
character of the place he occupies
彼がいる場所の特徴
you just asked a lot of questions
あなたはちょうどたくさんの質問をしました
is a later development
後の展開です
Of course it was impossible to take pictures at that time
もちろん当時は写真撮影は不可能でした
OK that 1663
わかりました、1663
you don't have a camera yet
あなたはまだカメラを持っていません
some jokes
冗談
I say but images are very important
とは言いますが、イメージは非常に重要です
Because we know that a statistical graph
統計グラフは次のことを知っているので、
A lot of Equation than you
あなたよりもたくさんの方程式
much better effect
はるかに良い効果
Because the picture can be understood by everyone
誰でもわかる絵なので
OK although a graph appears
グラフが出てもOK
There may be a lot of inferences behind
背後には多くの推論があるかもしれない
but i think
しかし、私は思います
A very important purpose of statistics is to
統計の非常に重要な目的は、
Let the average person know what adjustments you are making
あなたがどのような調整を行っているかを一般の人に知らせてください
So statistics has many, many components
したがって、統計には非常に多くの要素が含まれます
There's a big part of it that we don't understand
私たちが理解していない部分が大きい
But there must be some parts
でも部分もあるはずだ
For example, let's go to the official information now
たとえば、今すぐ公式情報に行きましょう
there must be some statistics
何らかの統計があるはずです
that as long as you go online now
今オンラインに接続している限り
Probably can be downloaded
たぶんダウンロードできると思います
For example it must have this part
たとえば、この部分が必要です
is to allow you to find the information you want
欲しい情報を見つけられるようにすることです
Then I would say that for everyone
それなら誰に対してもそう言うよ
You must at least know how to calculate the average
少なくとも平均の計算方法を知っておく必要があります
At least know how to calculate Medium
少なくともMediumの計算方法を知ってください
that's fine
それはいいです。
This is called narrative statistics
これを記述統計といいます
That is to say, give you a bunch of numbers
つまり、たくさんの数字を与えてください
you know which number is most likely
どの数字が最も可能性が高いか知っていますか
what is possible
何が可能ですか
that's an interesting question
それは興味深い質問です
What do you think is all the numbers add up
すべての数字を足すと何だと思いますか
divided by its observed value
観測値で割った値
still watching obsession
まだ執着を見ている
This itself is a controversial issue
これ自体が物議を醸す問題です
that's why i say
だから私は言うのです
Statistics must have this part
統計にはこの部分が必要です
but of course that means
しかしもちろんそれは意味します
The country should be doing this now
国は今すぐこれをやるべきだ
But it can also have some consequences
しかし、それは何らかの結果をもたらす可能性もあります
Because it's the shape of technology
それはテクノロジーの形だから
ok you do
わかりました、そうします
maybe its consequences you don't want
もしかしたらあなたが望まない結果になるかもしれません
Especially when it's not a democratic society
特に民主主義社会ではない場合には
ok
Ok
anymore question
もう質問
still have a question
まだ質問があります
you sign up
あなたは登録します
yes
はい
good
良い
Thank you teacher for your wonderful speech
先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました
Then what I want to ask is what you just introduced
そこで聞きたいのは、今紹介したことです
the place where the scholar was known
その学者が知られていた場所
You said he was a pastor and you mentioned that he was
あなたは彼が牧師だと言いました、そしてあなたは彼が牧師であると言いました
Cooking itself God himself has no way of knowing
料理自体は神自身が知る由もない
but you can see what he wants you to see
でも彼があなたに見てほしいものはわかるよ
So the question that comes to my mind is
そこで私の頭に浮かぶ質問は、
Doesn't that mean if God wants us to see a certain part
それは、神が私たちに特定の部分を見てほしいと望んでいるという意味ではないでしょうか
Then we can only live forever as he wants us to see
そうすれば、私たちは彼が私たちに望むように永遠に生きることしかできません
So in other words, Lin Gang also mentioned Sherlock Holmes
つまり、リン・ガンはシャーロック・ホームズについても言及したということですね
As long as the criminal can make Sherlock Holmes
犯人がホームズを作ることができる限り
only see what he wants him to see
彼が見てほしいものだけを見る
It is impossible for Holmes to discover the truth
ホームズが真実を発見することは不可能です
this is a very good question
これはとても良い質問です
So recite the information left behind
だから残された情報を暗唱してください
Or have subsequent researchers explored
あるいは後続の研究者が調査したのか
is it possible
出来ますか
It's that we can never know what we're looking at
それは、私たちが何を見ているのか決して分からないということです
What do you think about this in the theory of back knowledge?
これを裏知識論ではどう思いますか？
Great, I think this is a very, very critical question
なるほど、これは非常に非常に重要な質問だと思います
The first criminal's evidence is all here
最初の犯人の証拠はすべてここにある
OK so a detective's job isn't that complicated
探偵の仕事はそれほど複雑ではありません
You just have to be able to see tiny evidence
ほんの小さな証拠を見ることができればいいのです
you can make many inferences
多くの推論を行うことができます
This problem is relatively simple
この問題は比較的単純です
But you now know why the base
しかし、なぜベースなのかがわかりました。
comboxbase it doesn't write its stats
Comboxbase は統計情報を書き込まない
it writes theology
神学を書いている
the problem is very complicated
問題は非常に複雑です
about what god can show you
神があなたに示してくれる限り
that is a theological question
それは神学的な質問です
Of course for a Christian
もちろんキリスト教徒にとっても
for him
彼のために
God will never let you see things that will make you feel scared
神はあなたに恐怖を感じるものを決して見せません
but how do you know it's true
しかし、それが真実だとどうやってわかるのですか
that is a theological question
それは神学的な質問です
So there is a law that can be derived from its back
その裏から導き出せる法則がある
find a clue that says
という手がかりを見つける
God will show you one thing
神様は一つのことを教えてくれるでしょう
not for you to see once
一度見るものではありません
it will make you watch it many times
何度も見てしまうでしょう
and not just for you to see
あなただけが見るためではありません
it allows everyone to see
誰もが見ることができます
know what i mean
わかる
That is to say, this rule is applicable to everyone.
つまり、このルールは誰にでも当てはまります。
If everyone can use this law to deduce
誰もがこの法則を使って推測できるなら
Isn't this the best way?
これが最善の方法ではないでしょうか?
if the work of moose
ヘラジカの仕業なら
Just to tell everyone what God is
神とは何かをみんなに伝えるためだけに
So it actually has a theological purpose
つまり、実際には神学的目的があるのです
but i think it makes sense
でもそれは理にかなっていると思う
That means
つまり、
This thing is different from statistics after the 19th century
これは19世紀以降の統計とは違う
The statistics after the four seasons are probably very fixed
四季の後の統計はおそらく非常に固定されています
Statistics has several basic assumptions
統計にはいくつかの基本的な前提があります
From these assumptions it can then be deduced that
これらの仮定から次のことが推測できます。
what is the best statistical model
最良の統計モデルは何ですか
But like it doesn't come like this
でもこんなふうにはいかないみたいに
It is based on Prior belief
それは以前の信念に基づいています
What is Prior belief?
事前信念とは何ですか?
anything can
何でもできる
But the point is you can always renew your beliefs
しかし重要なのは、自分の信念はいつでも更新できるということです
So the point is to keep updating
重要なのは更新し続けることです
It's not an update, it's an update all the time
更新ではなく、常に更新です
Hello, I read Li Ke
こんにちは、李克を読みました。
It's hard
それは難しい
Get some enlightenment in this topic today
今日このトピックについて理解を深めましょう
In the past, I only heard that gorgeousness values ​​fairness and justice.
華やかさは公平性や正義を大切にするということを昔は聞いたことがあります。
What economics focuses on is efficiency
経済学が重視するのは効率性
that politics is a series of compromises
政治とは妥協の連続だということ
Then today I finally saw the original in the compromise
そして今日やっと妥協案でオリジナルを見ました
it has a statistical background
統計的な背景がある
And there is some basis for this competition theory
そして、この競争理論にはある程度の根拠があります
So the question I want to ask is
それで私が聞きたい質問は
Today the teacher mentioned that
今日先生が言ってた
Since it is an electoral system, it will affect the distribution of the entire political party
選挙制度なので政党全体の分布に影響する
then if we go back to
次に戻ってみると
If politics is just strategy itself
政治が戦略そのものだとしたら
there is a purpose behind it
その裏には目的がある
Let's go back to Taiwan
台湾に帰ろう
Taiwan is a multicultural society
台湾は多文化社会です
In such a multicultural society, we can't afford the old-fashioned infighting over there.
このような多文化社会では、向こうで昔ながらの内紛を許すわけにはいきません。
Based on the principle of no internal friction, it should be avoided that the two parties are just doing a rotation over there.
内部摩擦ゼロの原則に基づき、単に向こうでローテーションをするだけということは避けるべきだ。
Is that in the electoral system? I don't know from a political point of view.
それは選挙制度にあるのでしょうか? 政治的な観点からはわかりません。
Is it true that Taiwan is also going to be like a Huaguo?
台湾も華国みたいになるって本当ですか？
Will there be more cooperation with the party?
党との協力はさらに進むだろうか？
It's a little too late for you to ask the question
質問するには少し遅すぎます
because it's too late
もう手遅れだから
no i'm kidding
いや、冗談だよ
Why, because why is there such an electoral system now, have you ever wondered
なぜ、なぜ今そのような選挙制度があるのか​​、疑問に思ったことはありますか
Yes, why is it ordered by the big party, because he hates the small party
はい、なぜそれが大きなパーティーによって命令されるのですか、彼は小さなパーティーが嫌いだからです
Talking about the Wenxian here is that you talk about those who oppose the system
ここでウェンシアンについて語るということは、体制に反対する人々について語るということだ
So is there going to be Wenxian who has a lot of Wenxian love here?
では、ウェンシアン愛をたっぷりと持つウェンシアンはここに登場するのでしょうか？
In fact, he has a point, that is, I don't have time to talk about institutional theory today.
実際、彼の言うことは一理あります。つまり、今日は制度論について話す時間がありません。
Because if you really talk about it, sometimes it will be very sad.
本当のことを話すと、とても悲しいことになることがあるからです。
Because of some systems he is a minority
いくつかの制度のせいで彼は少数派だ
It's not a few people, it's a certain group of people. After it is established, it will be standardized.
それは少数の人々ではなく、一定の人々のグループであり、設定された後は標準化されます。
If you don't do this, no, you won't have a seat
そうしないと席がありません
So he will be very unfair to the third force or other minor parties
したがって、彼は第三勢力やその他の小政党に対して非常に不公平になるだろう
But then it's like you're talking about politics compromising
でもそうすると、まるで政治の妥協について話しているようだ
Why didn't he set a single constituency with two votes?
なぜ小選挙区を２票に設定しなかったのか。
pure unitary constituency
純粋な単一選挙区
Because we still have party-white negotiations
まだ党派間の交渉があるから
Xiaodang said it can't be done like this
シャオダンはこのようにはできないと言った
He said that if you can't set the joint force system in Germany
彼は、ドイツに統合軍システムを設置できない場合は、と述べた。
At least make a case
少なくとも主張する
What does case system mean
ケースシステムとはどういう意味ですか
Even if you still have part of the country
たとえまだ国の一部を持っていたとしても
Little party still has a chance
小さなパーティーにはまだチャンスがある
In other words, when will the small party have a chance
言い換えれば、小規模政党にチャンスはいつ来るのかということだ。
When the strength of your two major parties is about the same
二大政党の力がほぼ同じ場合
small party will have some chance
小さなパーティーにはチャンスがあるだろう
But the problem is because it's leisure
でも問題はそれがレジャーだから
Leisure is a super high threshold
レジャーは敷居が非常に高い
everyone should know
誰もが知っておくべきです
More than three-quarters of Congress agree
議会の4分の3以上が同意
then to
それから
almost impossible
ほぼ不可能である
when electing president
大統領を選出するとき
More than half of the electorate turned out to vote
有権者の半数以上が投票に行った
is possible to pass
通過可能です
So it's impossible if he didn't tie the election
つまり、彼が選挙で同点でなければ不可能だった
But you say it's impossible
でもあなたはそれは不可能だと言う
I'll see
見てみます
We can only say that now Taiwan
台湾のものとしか言えません。
The threshold for system reform is very high
制度改革の敷居は非常に高い
Then this threshold was set in 2005
その後、このしきい値は 2005 年に設定されました
not yet
まだ
That's all I can say, that's all I can say as a scholar
私に言えるのはこれだけ、学者として言えることはこれだけです
Well, I think of course there are many ways.
まあ、もちろん色々な方法があると思います。
But now that we have a system
でも今はシステムがあるから
Everyone is using this system
みんなこのシステム使ってるよ
I think it's better to follow it
一緒に行った方が良いと思います
anymore question
もう質問
right
右
Yeah
うん
EITM
EITM
Because we now sometimes have to create some nouns
時々、名詞を作成する必要があるため、
it does not omit at all
全然省略してないよ
EITM就是Imperial Implications of Theoretical Models
EITM は理論モデルの帝国的な意味合いです
Imperial Implications of Theoretical Models
理論モデルの帝国的な意味合い
is the empirical implication of your theoretical model
理論モデルの経験的な意味合いです
it speaks vernacular
それは現地語を話します
for example
例えば
it has a theory, right?
それは理論がありますよね？
Give me a test, that's what it means
テストをしてください、それが意味するものです
Just say you want Imperial Implications
帝国の暗示が欲しいと言ってください
sounds deep, doesn't it
奥深いですね。
It's what you test
それはあなたがテストするものです
what to test test me and theory
何をテストするか私と理論をテストする
It's called Theoretical Models
それは理論モデルと呼ばれます
That is, your model is not just a model
つまり、あなたのモデルは単なるモデルではありません
It's from Theoretic
理論からです
For example, we just talked about Divacient
たとえば、先ほど Divacient について話しました。
Is a Theoretical Models
理論モデルです
Front it has Theoretic
フロントには理論があります
wired at the back
後面有線
help him change it to MODE
彼がモードに変更するのを手伝ってください
can detect
検出できる
What is detected?
何が検出されるのでしょうか?
right or wrong
正しいか間違っているか
So it is IMPIRICLE
つまりインピリクルです
it is an empirical test
それは経験的なテストです
So EITM sorry
EITM ごめんなさい
Because of this in political science has become a JACAN
このため、政治学はJACANになりました
Because I feel that POWPON
POWPONって感じだから
I can't fit so many words
あまりにも多くの言葉では収まりません
it's not mysterious at all
全然神秘的じゃないよ
there's nothing wrong with it
何も問題ありません
no problem
問題ない
time has come
時間が来ました
i want to clarify one thing
一つはっきりさせておきたいことがあります
That's what Mr. Lin said just now
林先生が今そうおっしゃいました
like in the future
将来のように
I do not know him
私は彼を知らない
But because when he was studying, he
しかし、彼が勉強していたとき、
In fact, when I was studying
実は私が勉強していたとき
I help my wife with reading
私は妻の読書を手伝います
but i haven't seen either
でも私も見ていない
then like in the future
それから未来のように
He and I are around there
彼と私はそこら中にいます
I don't even remember coming with me in the hallway
廊下まで一緒に来たことさえ覚えていない
Always
いつも
but i'm not
でも僕はそうじゃない
I didn't come to talk about anything
何も話しに来たわけではない
because he waited for me to come back
彼は私が戻ってくるのを待っていたから
yes i have graduated
はい、卒業しました
After returning to Taiwan
台湾帰国後
one hour later
一段時間以後
but before he died
しかし彼が死ぬ前に
We had a teacher tell me
先生に教えてもらいました
he not long ago
彼はつい最近まで
i am on campus
私はキャンパスにいます
You see a continent
大陸が見えます
19 photos taken together
一緒に撮った写真19枚
beat him up
彼を殴る
He probably didn't really take a beating
彼はおそらく実際には殴られなかった
probably him
おそらく彼
it's this special person
それはこの特別な人です
Look at the features
特徴を見てください
He doesn't want people on the water level
彼は人が水面にいるのを望んでいない
Scared him on the way
途中で彼を怖がらせた
yes
はい
So I pushed it around
それで私はそれを押し広げました
As a result, he soon became an economist
その結果、彼はすぐに経済学者になった
When I received a big prize to do business
ビジネスで高額な賞をもらったとき
From Canada Airport
カナダ空港から
When it's time to go back to Briston
ブリストンに戻る時間になったら
died in a car accident
自動車事故で死亡した
But there was a mathematician who colonized the world
しかし世界を植民地化した数学者がいた
I can't tell if he is
彼がそうであるかどうかはわかりません
He was also a professor in Princeton's Department of Mathematics
彼はプリンストン大学の数学学部の教授でもありました
he told me
彼は私に言った
he will think
彼は考えるだろう
if he was joking
もし彼が冗談を言っていたら
I told him
私は彼に言った
he said
彼は言った
If you don't get that prize
その賞品を手に入れられなかったら
probably won't die
おそらく死なないでしょう
he because we from
彼は私たちが出身だから
from that airport
あの空港から
back to princeton
プリンストンに戻る
Are doing Airport
空港やってます
Just a dozen people do it
たった十数人がやってる
Eighty and thirty yuan per person
1人あたり83元
those are poor
彼らは貧しいです
Don't even talk about how much money you don't have
どれだけお金がないのかについても話さないでください
yes then what
はい、それでは何ですか
How is he willing to spend 350 dollars
彼は350ドルをどうやって使うつもりですか
do that economy
その経済をやれ
probably
おそらく
got that
わかった
Said that he is still proportional to 10 people
まだ10人に比例してるって言ってた
8 times everyone
全員8回
so what
だから何
money again
またお金
So do 350
350もそうだよ
3 400 mass momentum
3 400塊的機運
Involuntary movement vehicle
免機的機運車錢
So this one took him
それで、これが彼を連れて行きました
life is dead
人生は死んでいる
that
それか
Everyone is interested to see
誰もが興味を持って見ています
His book should have Chinese Art Edition
彼の本には中国美術編があるはずだ
beautiful
美しい
he is very legendary
彼はとても伝説的です
very very interesting
とてもとても興味深い
There is a movie version
映画版もあるよ
The movie version is not allowed
映画版は不可
At least that Rossel Coro doesn't look like it at all
少なくともロッセル・コロは全く似ていない
OK OK
はいはい
very very thank you all
とてもとてもありがとう皆さん
very exciting today
今日はとてもエキサイティングな
Thanks
ありがとう